<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Home on Noah Rahm</title><link>https://noahrahm.com/</link><description>Recent content in Home on Noah Rahm</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://noahrahm.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>20+ Free Resources for Digital Design</title><link>https://noahrahm.com/posts/free-resources-for-digital-design/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://noahrahm.com/posts/free-resources-for-digital-design/</guid><description>&lt;p>As a visual designer, having a good set of resources within arm&amp;rsquo;s reach is not only helpful but necessary.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>While there are a ton of really great paid design services and resources that can make life a lot easier, the focus of this list is on &lt;strong>the best free resources&lt;/strong> that I&amp;rsquo;ve personally collected over time. Many of these I&amp;rsquo;ve been using for years for my own &lt;a href="https://noahrahm.com/work/">design work&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Whether you&amp;rsquo;re a web, app, UI, UX designer, or none of the above, there&amp;rsquo;s likely at least a few things here you could consider adding to your toolkit.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Special thanks to all the individuals and companies that made these resources available for designers like us to use free of charge!&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="typography">Typography&lt;/h3>
&lt;figure>&lt;img src="https://noahrahm.com/posts/free-resources-for-digital-design/fontjoy.jpg"
alt="A screenshot of FontJoy"/>&lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>FontJoy in action. Yes, sometimes it comes up with wild combinations&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://fontjoy.com/">FontJoy&lt;/a> is a really nice font pairing web application tool that generates font combinations with deep learning. If you know what style you&amp;rsquo;re after (and have some patience), it can come up with some nice font pairs for you to consider.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://typespiration.com/">Typespiration&lt;/a> If you&amp;rsquo;re needing some inspiration for type, you can take a look at Typespiration for some designs and guides for font combinations.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://typescale.com/">Type Scale&lt;/a> is a visual calculator you can use to size your typography.&lt;/p>
&lt;figure>&lt;img src="https://noahrahm.com/posts/free-resources-for-digital-design/typescale.jpg"
alt="A screenshot of Typescale"/>&lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Typescale&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.fontsinthewild.com/">Fontsinthewild.com&lt;/a> Sometimes you just have to see a font used in order to get inspiration to use it in your design. That is the basic premise of fontsinthewild.com, where you browse screenshots of different fonts used on sites &amp;ldquo;in the wild&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://v-fonts.com/">v-fonts&lt;/a> Experiment with variable fonts.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://fontspark.netlify.app/">FontSpark&lt;/a> is a simple tool to find different fonts.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.pairandcompare.net/">Pair and Compare&lt;/a> is a great way to mix and match different Google fonts to find the best combination for your design.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Want a good reading resource to improve your typography skills? Read &lt;a href="https://practicaltypography.com/">Butterick&amp;rsquo;s Practical Typography&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="color-resources">Color resources&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://palx.jxnblk.com/">palx.jxnblk.com&lt;/a> is a very helpful tool for generating a full-spectrum color palette from a single color. I mainly use it when I need to quickly generate a range of grays for a UI design.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://toolness.github.io/accessible-color-matrix/">Accessible color matrix&lt;/a> Accessibility is an important part of choosing colors for a website or app design. This accessible color matrix tool allows you to check if your color combinations conform to accessibility standards.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://hihayk.github.io/scale">ihayk.github.io/scale&lt;/a> A creative way to experiment with different color ranges.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="icon-sets">Icon sets&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://simpleicons.org/">Simple Icons&lt;/a> Very useful and vast collection of 2750 SVG icons for popular brands. I haven&amp;rsquo;t found any brands I&amp;rsquo;ve ever needed to &lt;em>not&lt;/em> be in the Simple Icons collection.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://phosphoricons.com/">Phosphoricons&lt;/a> Open-source icon family offering 6 weights: thin, light, regular, bold, fill, and duotone. Needless to say, it is a very useful and large (1,248+) collection worth bookmarking.&lt;/p>
&lt;figure>&lt;img src="https://noahrahm.com/posts/free-resources-for-digital-design/phosphor-icons.jpg"
alt="A screenshot of the Phosphor icons website"/>&lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Phosphor icon family. Go bookmark it —it&amp;rsquo;s worth the bookmark.&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;h3 id="software">Software&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://icons8.com/lunacy">Lunacy&lt;/a> (A.K.A. Sketch for Windows). Although I don’t care for the name, it’s my primary design tool. Being a native Windows application makes it fast and smooth to work with. Lunacy works &lt;em>completely offline&lt;/em> and has almost everything I&amp;rsquo;ve ever needed for creating web and graphic designs, having worked with it for the past 3 years.&lt;/p>
&lt;figure>&lt;img src="https://noahrahm.com/posts/free-resources-for-digital-design/lunacy.jpg"
alt="A screenshot of Lunacy open with a logo design document"/>&lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Lunacy—my (current) go-to design tool open to my logo design for Hilltop Motion.&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://penpot.app">PenPot&lt;/a> is an open-source, web-based design and prototyping tool based on open standards.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="templates">Templates&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>If you need something for a specific design software, there are sites that provide free UI kits, icons, templates, mockups, style guides, illustrations, and more. My experience is that you do have to look through a lot of &amp;ldquo;okay&amp;rdquo; stuff to find the gold, though.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="sketch">Sketch&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://sketchelements.com/">SketchElements&lt;/a> is a place to find free Sketch resources. The files can be used with either Lunacy or Sketch.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="figma">Figma&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Similar to SketchElements.com above, &lt;a href="https://figmaelements.com/">FigmaElements&lt;/a> offers free Figma resources.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="mockups">Mockups&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.ls.graphics/free-mockups">ls.graphics&lt;/a> Free, high-quality mockups from ls.graphics.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://mockuphone.com/">MockUPhone&lt;/a> is by far the best free resource I have discovered for generating device mockups. The site allows you to wrap your design in a variety of mobile device frames, including iPhones, iPads, Android phones, laptops, and wearables. The mockups are licensed under the Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 Unported License, making them usable for practically any project.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Another resource for generating Android mockups is the official &lt;a href="https://developer.android.com/distribute/marketing-tools/device-art-generator">Android Device Art Generator&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="assets">Assets&lt;/h3>
&lt;figure>&lt;img src="https://noahrahm.com/posts/free-resources-for-digital-design/haikei.jpg"
alt="A screenshot of Haikei generating a layered peaks svg background"/>&lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>You can generate all sorts of backgrounds with Haikei.&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>Both &lt;a href="https://superdesigner.co/">superdesigner.co&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://haikei.app/">haikei.app&lt;/a> let you generate SVG assets like backgrounds, blobs, patterns, gradients, and shapes for your designs.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="conclusion">Conclusion&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Thanks for reading. I hope you enjoyed this list of design resources and tools.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>This aims to be a growing list of the best free resources for design, so check back for updates.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Do you have any free design tools or resources you use that I didn&amp;rsquo;t mention? Feel free to comment below.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Journey Behind Velocity Lapse Part 4</title><link>https://noahrahm.com/posts/journey-behind-velocity-lapse-part-4/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://noahrahm.com/posts/journey-behind-velocity-lapse-part-4/</guid><description>&lt;p>You can read the previous posts, &lt;a href="https://noahrahm.com/posts/journey-behind-velocity-lapse-part-1/">Part 1&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://noahrahm.com/posts/journey-behind-velocity-lapse-part-2/">Part 2&lt;/a>, and &lt;a href="https://noahrahm.com/posts/journey-behind-velocity-lapse-part-3/">Part 3&lt;/a> to get context of my journey creating &lt;a href="https://velocitylapse.com">Velocity Lapse&lt;/a> up to this point.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you have any comments or suggestions, feel free to leave a comment below.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="continued-progress">Continued progress&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Starting in 2023, I decided to be more intentional with when I work on Velocity Lapse to avoid burnout.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="slower-pace">Slower pace&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Obviously, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t continue the pace that I had during the first 6 months of initial development. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t justify spending more time on it than a set reasonable amount per week. It also happened that I had other big projects for work come my way.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And so, I slowed down the pace of development and shifted my priorities to fit.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="flurry-analytics">Flurry Analytics&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Ultimately, I decided that it doesn&amp;rsquo;t benefit the users for me to &lt;em>not&lt;/em> have the information I need to improve the app and fix crashes. When it comes down to privacy vs. being able to fix issues quicker, I think most users would choose the latter. So I added Flurry analytics to the app.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="missed-launch-dates">Missed launch dates&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>You may be wondering: &amp;ldquo;Have I forgotten about the full release? When will that happen?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="not-yet-stable-enough">Not yet stable enough&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Well, at this point I didn&amp;rsquo;t believe it was ready for an out-of-beta release.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For one thing, I had noticed that the user perceived crash rate was around 6-7%, which was over the Google Play maximum threshold.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Most of the issues were crashes during export. Obviously, not a great thing to see.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In short: Velocity Lapse just wasn&amp;rsquo;t up to production quality yet. I didn&amp;rsquo;t feel right launching to production with that much unstability.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="unrealistic-projections">Unrealistic projections&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Although I had projected an (unrealistic) launch date for somewhere around the end of Roman &amp;ldquo;January&amp;rdquo;, things were not favorable for that deadline.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I felt more confident setting the release date to the 7th of Roman &amp;ldquo;March&amp;rdquo;, but that did not end up happening. Even my thought that the app would be ready for full release by Spring fell through.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Part of this is that the &amp;ldquo;MVP&amp;rdquo; feature list fell prey to &amp;ldquo;scope creep&amp;rdquo; and I under-estimated the amount of time involved to implement some of the features and work through the bugs. This was good thing though, since it gave me more time to &amp;ldquo;flesh-out&amp;rdquo; the app.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="working-on-the-features-and-fixes">Working on the features and fixes&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Early Roman February, I zeroed in on the features and fixes that were most necessary for a good user experience, working on them one by one.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="camera-re-write">Camera re-write&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>I began to work on creating my own custom camera package to fix some of the issues with the camera and add features like the ability to capture with the screen off, multi-lense support, and manual white balance control.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I dove into Kotlin and the camera2 API to understand it better. Starting small, I first created a basic camera as a native Kotlin project to work out the kinks of the camera2 API. (As of the time of this writing, this is still in the works.)&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="upgrading-to-flutter-37">Upgrading to Flutter 3.7&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Upgrading to Flutter 3.7 only required a few lines of deprecated code to be changed, which was nice as I didn&amp;rsquo;t need anything extra to work on.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="a-silly-issue-resolved">A silly issue resolved&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>One of the export issues ended up being the result of a single character typo. Once I corrected that, 4k export worked smoothly. To put it lightly, I was overjoyed and a little upset that such a small mistake caused so much problems.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, that didn&amp;rsquo;t solve every issue as I discovered that export crashed with 720p and 1080p with certain bitrates, somewhat randomly. I later mostly resolved this.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="updating-the-price-of-pro">Updating the price of PRO&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>On Roman Feb. 5th I raised the in-app purchase of Velocity Lapse PRO to $5.99. This turned out to be a very good decision as the app was indeed worth more than the previous $3.99, based on user feedback. Plus, it allowed me to invest in a test device to further improve Velocity Lapse.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="a-new-test-device">A new test device&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Until this point, I had to rely on using friend&amp;rsquo;s devices to test features that were limited to certain devices, such as 4K. However, relying on bits of time with someone else&amp;rsquo;s device was not reliable or optimal.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So I decided to look for a phone to buy which supports 4k video so I could test the full functionality of Velocity Lapse myself. Thankfully I had made enough money from the in-app purchase at this point to re-invest.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="my-experience-ordering-from-back-market">My experience ordering from Back Market&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>A friend had mentioned Back Market as a place to buy refurbished electronics, so I took a look to see what they had.&lt;/p>
&lt;h5 id="phone-requirements">Phone requirements&lt;/h5>
&lt;p>My requirements for the test device were:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>4K video support&lt;/strong> so I could do the 4K testing&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>A relatively new model&lt;/strong> as I didn&amp;rsquo;t want it to be too outdated for testing&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>3.3mm headphone jack&lt;/strong> so that I could hook up an external mic for recording videos&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="my-purchase-from-back-market">My purchase from Back Market&lt;/h5>
&lt;p>After looking around to see what phone model would suit my needs, I settled for a Samsung Galaxy A53 phone which has 4k video support and listed the other requirements in the Back Market description.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The one I chose from Back Market was a &amp;ldquo;Good&amp;rdquo; condition 128GB 5G Samsung Galaxy A53 tracfone phone.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My initial perception of Back Market wasn&amp;rsquo;t the best. I was wary of buying from Back Market as some people online said it was a scam and I hadn&amp;rsquo;t bought refurbished before. I also didn&amp;rsquo;t like how difficult it seemed to contact them. However, in the end I decided to go for it.&lt;/p>
&lt;h5 id="not-as-listed">Not as listed&lt;/h5>
&lt;p>Once I received the phone, I set it up and began using it to test. However, I didn&amp;rsquo;t realize until a day or two later that there was no 3.3mm headphone jack as was listed on Back Market (and still is at the time of this writing).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I opened a support request (which was a very confusing process) and they eventually said: &amp;ldquo;It appears that it was a listing error as in fact, this model does not contain 3.5mm Jack for headphones.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I decided to keep the phone since I didn&amp;rsquo;t have the time to deal with the hassle of returning it and re-purchasing another model.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, at the time of this writing I looked at their listing for the A53 (the same as I purchased) and it still lists the 3.3mm headphone jack. I thought they would have removed the false information by now. So, I contacted them again about it. Hopefully they fix the listing.&lt;/p>
&lt;h5 id="conclusion-on-the-phone">Conclusion on the phone&lt;/h5>
&lt;p>I haven&amp;rsquo;t had any issues with the phone itself so far. Overall, ordering from Back Market was an OK experience. Not sure that I would buy from them again, though.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="thoughts-on-negative-software-reviews">Thoughts on negative software reviews&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Having received a few rather unfair reviews the past year, I thought I would share my thoughts on negative reviews.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="please-please-no-hit-and-run">Please, please no hit-and-run&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>If you use software long enough, you will likely be inclined to write a bad review. I&amp;rsquo;ve done it myself more than I would have liked to. Problems &lt;em>will&lt;/em> occur. Issues &lt;em>will&lt;/em> arise. It&amp;rsquo;s inevitable and unavoidable in software. But &lt;em>please&lt;/em> don&amp;rsquo;t be the user that does a &amp;ldquo;hit and run&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Probably &lt;em>the most frustrating&lt;/em> reviews, in my opinion, are those that say a few negative words (sometimes using profanity) without explaining what the issues is, and then leave no way for the developer to follow up with them. These individuals either give a fake email or delete the review so you can&amp;rsquo;t respond to their comments.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Unfortunately for the developer, it does no good because no actionable feedback is given and they cannot ask for any either. They are left wondering, &amp;ldquo;okay, so what exactly is the problem?&amp;rdquo; It could be thousands of things.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ultimately, these kinds of &amp;ldquo;reviews&amp;rdquo; don&amp;rsquo;t do much good, other than to vent feelings and/or frustration because they left no way to potentially solve the issue.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thankfully, I have only received a few of these myself thus far, but it isn&amp;rsquo;t a nice feeling.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So, please be the user that gives a review with specific, actionable criticism on what should be improved. Constructive criticism, even if it&amp;rsquo;s harsh, can be good. Hit and run negativity is not.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="updating-the-website-for-real">Updating the website (for real)&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>I updated the website, yet again. This time I went through the hassle and took the time to write proper copy for the homepage, explaining the benefits of the app. Honestly, it wasn&amp;rsquo;t that hard since at this point the app has so many nice features and I had plently of user feedback to back it up.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Multiple people had commented that Velocity Lapse was &amp;ldquo;no doubt&amp;rdquo; the best time lapse app for Android. Though, I didn&amp;rsquo;t think it was appropriate to put that on the website&amp;hellip;just yet, at least. :)&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="v03-and-on-to-v04">v0.3 and on to v0.4&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To close off the 0.3.x series, I added crash reporting and implemented multi select and delete for the editor.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For the 0.4.x series of releases, I aimed to focus on making quality-of-life improvements and fixing bugs.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="prioritizing-of-feature-requests-and-fixes">Prioritizing of feature requests and fixes&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Sometimes, I would get flooded with feature requests and it started to get overwhelming. So, I adopted a methodology of prioritizing them based on:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>1)&lt;/strong> Fixes that would otherwise cause a bad experience for &lt;strong>most users&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>2)&lt;/strong> Features that would improve the experience of &lt;strong>the most users&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Basically, &amp;ldquo;high-impact&amp;rdquo; requests. Oftentimes, that means working on something else in order to fix or add something, but at least it is a little less overwhelming.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="not-really-mvp-anymore">Not really MVP anymore&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>As of the time of this writing, I don&amp;rsquo;t think the app is really an MVP anymore. I made a second pass through most of the app&amp;rsquo;s views and functionality, re-writing and re-designing them with the feedback I&amp;rsquo;ve gathered over the last year. But, that&amp;rsquo;s OK.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ultimately, &amp;ldquo;Ideas are cheap: execution is everything&amp;rdquo;. So, having something implemented in the app is better than the idea in my head. At least then I know if it&amp;rsquo;s working out or not.&lt;/p>
&lt;figure>&lt;img src="https://noahrahm.com/posts/journey-behind-velocity-lapse-4/v045&amp;#43;38-app-screenshots.jpg"
alt="Screenshots of Velocity Lapse v0.5.0"/>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;h3 id="updating-the-price-of-pro-1">Updating the price of PRO&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>On May 17th, 2023 I decided to raise the price of Velocity Lapse PRO to $7.99. At this point, the app was beginning to be more fleshed out and included saving to SD card as a PRO feature.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="flutter-310">Flutter 3.10&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Upgrading to Flutter 3.10 was very straightforward. Flutter and Dart have been amazing to work with. Although I&amp;rsquo;ve run into a few areas that are rough around the edges, overall I couldn&amp;rsquo;t be happier with the development experience building an app like this with Flutter.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="hacker-noon-startup-of-the-year-nomination">Hacker Noon startup of the year nomination&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>At the end of Roman May, I was greeted with an email from Hacker Noon that Velocity Lapse had been nominated for Startup of the Year 2023 Ava, MO. This was a nice surprise and awful nice of someone to do. Although it was just a nomination, the fact that Hacker Noon though Velocity Lapse to be worthy enough to accepted it was a pretty neat feeling. So, thanks to whoever nominated Velocity Lapse!&lt;/p>
&lt;figure>&lt;img src="https://noahrahm.com/posts/journey-behind-velocity-lapse-4/hn-nomination-instagram-post.jpg"
alt="Hacker Noon startup of the year 2023 nomination"/>&lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>I posted Velocity Lapse&amp;rsquo;s Hacker Noon startup of the year 2023 nomination on Instagram&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>By the way, if it&amp;rsquo;s still 2023 when you&amp;rsquo;re reading this and you&amp;rsquo;d like to vote for Velocity Lapse, you can do so &lt;a href="https://hackernoon.com/startups/north-america/north-america-ava-mo-usa">here&lt;/a>. Thanks!&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="big-releases">Big releases&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Leading up to the 1 year anniversary of Velocity Lapse, I worked towards the goal of finishing off the leftover &amp;ldquo;MVP&amp;rdquo; features, adding the most requested features, and re-designing the app to be more presentable and easier to use.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="v04538">v0.4.5+38&lt;/h4>
&lt;figure>&lt;img src="https://noahrahm.com/posts/journey-behind-velocity-lapse-4/0-4-5-releases-notes.jpg"
alt="Screenshot of the v0.4.5&amp;#43;38 release notes"/>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>Released the first week of Roman June, v0.4.5+38 was a huge release with tons of interface improvements and additions, as well as the new editor playback feature.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="v05040-1st-year-anniversary-release">v0.5.0+40 1st year anniversary release&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Throughout the past year, the single most-requested feature was the ability to capture time lapses with the screen shut off. Initially, I had a difficult time working out how to do it with Android&amp;rsquo;s security and battery limitations, but I was pleased when I was able to find a solution that worked well -just in time for the v0.5.0 1st year anniversary release!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Seemed like a fitting way to say &amp;ldquo;thank you&amp;rdquo; to all the users who shared feedback to make the app what it is.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="1st-year-anniversary-of-velocity-lapse">1st year anniversary of Velocity Lapse&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>On 6/7/2023 I did a &lt;a href="https://youtube.com/live/ASSWkkVYWJg?feature=share">livestream event&lt;/a> on YouTube sharing a presentation of some of the background behind Velocity Lapse, the v0.5.0 features, and future plans.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Due to announcing it only the night before, practically no-one knew about it. This was probably a good thing since it was my first live stream. Even though I knew there probably wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be anyone actually watching it live, I still wanted to do it to gain the experience.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, it went fairly well with only a few technical glitches. Certainly not a perfect presentation (or high quality audio).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I can see that I need to work on not saying &amp;ldquo;so&amp;rdquo; so much (no pun intended). I also probably didn&amp;rsquo;t need to share some of the more technical details which would bore most people. Well, now I know for next time.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="looking-back-on-the-past-year">Looking back on the past year&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Over the past year of development, I&amp;rsquo;ve learned a lot about entrepreneurship, app development, and marketing. I truly feel blessed that I&amp;rsquo;ve achieved a certain level of &amp;ldquo;success&amp;rdquo; already. (Success to me is impacting other people&amp;rsquo;s lives in a positive way -and showing them the love of Yahushua, if the opportunity arises).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve also been privileged to see glimpses of the impact of Velocity Lapse in the lives of others. From someone capturing timelapses of their art, to creating a timelapse to document their house remodel, to a timelapse filmmaker capturing the beauty of creation -It is a bit mind boggling that people, literally &amp;ldquo;on the other side of the world&amp;rdquo; use the app.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="statistics">Statistics&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>For the data/stats people around, I imagine you&amp;rsquo;ve been holding your breath to hear the stats. Well, here they are.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Google Play&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Total downloads since first public on Google Play (since Aug. 2022): &lt;strong>21,200+&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Total current installs: &lt;strong>4,700+&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Development&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Amount of individually logged code changes (commits): &lt;strong>780&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Number of closed issues: &lt;strong>85&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Development time: &lt;strong>A lot. ;)&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Revenue&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Gross revenue since I added Velocity Lapse PRO (since Oct. 2022): &lt;strong>~$700&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Note: I&amp;rsquo;m not giving exact numbers and rounding them to an even amount.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="conclusion-on-the-past-year">Conclusion on the past year&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Making even a decent time lapse app takes a lot of time, effort, and dedication.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Focusing on creating a &amp;ldquo;great app&amp;rdquo; seems to make marketing a bit easier. Thus far, I haven&amp;rsquo;t done much actual promotion, but organic Google Play searches and word-of-mouth are the best marketing I could ask for.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Although it has yet to generate enough revenue to make it worth my time and headaches from a business perspective, I am blessed to be able to continue to work on it with other motivations.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>1)&lt;/strong> To help others&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>2)&lt;/strong> I want the app for my own use&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>3)&lt;/strong> I get some enjoyment out of the process of creating the app&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t mind working on Velocity Lapse more if it became an actual, sustainable business. Probably not a realistic expectation, but it is a possibility, Yahweh-willing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I guess we&amp;rsquo;ll see how the next year unfolds.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="a-look-forward">A look forward&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>My goals for the coming months are:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Get Velocity Lapse stable and ready for the full release.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Re-design and improve the Timelapse and Manual capture views.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>(Hopefully) complete a full re-write of the camera code.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Talk to some people in the timelapse and mobile timelapse niche and see what they think of Velocity Lapse.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Launch into production.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Once launched, promote it on Product Hunt.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>And go from there.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Obviously, you can see how well &lt;em>my&lt;/em> plans have come to pass thus far, so I&amp;rsquo;m going to say &amp;ldquo;Yahweh-willing&amp;rdquo; to all of this.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="the-journey-continues">The journey continues&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Thank you for reading. I hope you&amp;rsquo;ve enjoyed this post and have gained something from this journey so far. I know I have.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you have a suggestion, a comment or some advice, relating either to the app or this post, I&amp;rsquo;d love to hear what you have to share either in the comments below or via &lt;a href="mailto:hi@noahrahm.com">email&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Stay tuned for part 5 of this series. Let me know in the comments below if you have any comments.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>&lt;em>A big thanks to numerous individuals for their support and advice, making this journey possible. Special thanks to &lt;a href="https://github.com/sundrycode">@sundrycode&lt;/a> for which I am grateful for his help developing the Android native side of the app and taking part in testing. And Yahweh, our Heavenly Father from whom all knowledge and every good thing comes.&lt;/em>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Looking Ahead</title><link>https://noahrahm.com/posts/looking-ahead/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://noahrahm.com/posts/looking-ahead/</guid><description>&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Two-hundred and fifty&amp;rdquo;, I replied.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>He paused and nodded, giving me the opportunity to comment further.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I told him a brand new recliner of the same type costs upwards of $800, but I couldn&amp;rsquo;t imagine how someone could pay that much for a recliner. I thought, &amp;ldquo;800 dollars seems like a lot of money to pay for a single piece of furniture.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>He replied with a neat perspective I had evidently forgotten the moment before.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>He explained how, when you think about it, if the recliner lasts you 10 years and you use it even 1 hour a day and it makes your life better then in reality you are only paying cents per day for the recliner. And even if you didn&amp;rsquo;t use it that much, it provided comfortable seating that contributed to your happiness and, in many cases, your health.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>He was right. It&amp;rsquo;s all a matter of &lt;em>perspective&lt;/em> to see the &lt;em>value&lt;/em> of investing in the long term rather than just thinking about the upfront cost.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>According to &lt;a href="https://cozyseating.com/how-long-should-recliner-last/">this site&lt;/a>, a recliner should last 7-15 years.
Taking the average of that, which is 11 years, and saying that someone uses the recliner just twice everyday (a pretty a modest estimate for most people) I thought I would do the math:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre tabindex="0">&lt;code>365 days x 11 years x 2 uses per day = 8,030 uses
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;pre tabindex="0">&lt;code>$800.00/8,030 = $0.09962...
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;p>So, if the recliner originally cost $800.00 and it was used &lt;em>just twice per day&lt;/em> for the estimated 11 year lifetime of the recliner, that would be &lt;strong>less than 10 cents per use&lt;/strong>. For someone that used it more or had it longer, it would be even less.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Indeed, in order to justify the upfront cost, you would need to have the long term benefits in mind -how the recliner would make your life better. If someone only looked at the here and now, 800 dollars they would have to give up in the &lt;em>short-term&lt;/em>, then they would likely miss seeing the real value of investing in it for their &lt;em>long-term&lt;/em> comfort. (I hope I&amp;rsquo;m not starting to sound like a recliner advertisement&amp;hellip;)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>His point stuck with me for the rest of the day. It really reminded me of this life and our walk to Yahweh, our Heavenly Father, looking ahead into eternity.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yes, we endure trials and persecution for His name&amp;rsquo;s sake. Yes, we give up our flesh, deny ourselves, and take up our &lt;a href="https://biblehub.com/greek/4716.htm">stauros&lt;/a> daily to follow Yahushua. However, when you look at this life as the passing vapor it is and into eternity, then you see that the passing afflictions, trials and things we give up now now are nothing in comparison to what awaits us in eternity. Nothing is worth holding on to in this world.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>2 Cor. 4:16-18&lt;/strong> Therefore we do not lose heart. Even though our outward man is perishing, yet the inward man is being renewed day by day. For our &lt;strong>light affliction, which is but for a moment, is working for us a far more exceeding and eternal weight of glory&lt;/strong>, while we do not look at the things which are seen, but at the things which are not seen. &lt;strong>For the things which are seen are temporary, but the things which are not seen are eternal&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s all about &lt;em>perspective&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The earthly, here and now isn&amp;rsquo;t so valuable when compared to the spiritual, heavenly things of Yahweh. As the hymn says, &lt;em>&amp;ldquo;and the things of earth grow strangely dim, in the light of His glory and grace&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Too often we focus on what&amp;rsquo;s going on in our lives or look at the world and question whether it is worth it. However, if we cannot find joy and strength in our present circumstances, then we can look to our bright future, just as our Savior Yahushua did in His moments of agony and anguish.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Matt. 26:39&lt;/strong> He went a little farther and fell on His face, and prayed, saying, &amp;ldquo;O My Father, if it is possible, let this cup pass from Me; nevertheless, &lt;strong>not as I will, but as You will.&lt;/strong>&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Probably some of the most heart-stirring words ever. He gave up His will in surrender to the Father.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Hebrews 12:2&lt;/strong> Looking unto Yahushua, the author and finisher of our faith, &lt;strong>who for the joy that was set before Him endured the &lt;a href="https://biblehub.com/greek/4716.htm">stauros&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>, despising the shame, and has sat down at the right hand of the throne of Yahweh.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>We should remember that if all Yahweh did was deliver us from our sins then we ought to be more than thankful. But He also gave us His great and precious promises, including eternal life through His Son Yahushua.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>2 Peter 1:2-3&lt;/strong> Grace and peace be multiplied to you in the knowledge of Yahweh and of Yahushua our Master, as His divine power has given to us all things that pertain to life and godliness, through the knowledge of Him who called us by glory and virtue, by &lt;strong>which have been given to us exceedingly great and precious promises&lt;/strong>, that through these you may be partakers of the divine nature, having escaped the corruption that is in the world through lust.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>1 John 3:1-3&lt;/strong> &lt;strong>Behold what manner of love the Father has bestowed on us, that we should be called children of Yahweh!&lt;/strong> Therefore the world does not know us, because it did not know Him. Beloved, now we are children of Yahweh; and it has not yet been revealed what we shall be, but we know that when He is revealed, &lt;strong>we shall be like Him, for we shall see Him as He is&lt;/strong>. And everyone who has this hope in Him purifies himself, just as He is pure.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>When we realize that we deserve condemnation and death but He gives us life instead, we see how amazing His love, grace, and mercy is.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>1 John 4:19&lt;/strong> We love Him because &lt;strong>He first loved us.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Romans 5:6-11&lt;/strong> For when we were still without strength, in due time Messiah died for the unrighteous. For scarcely for a righteous man will one die; yet perhaps for a good man someone would even dare to die. But &lt;strong>Yahweh demonstrates His own love toward us, in that while we were still sinners, Messiah died for us.&lt;/strong> Much more then, having now been justified by His blood, we shall be saved from wrath through Him. For if when we were enemies we were reconciled to Yahweh through the death of His Son, much more, having been reconciled, &lt;strong>we shall be saved by His life&lt;/strong>. And not only that, but we also rejoice in Yahweh through our Master Yahushua Messiah, through whom we have now received the reconciliation.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>The sad thing is, many people do see the value in giving up $800 (or more) for a recliner&amp;rsquo;s earthly comfort, but they do not want to give up themselves and humbly walk with Yahushua for &lt;em>far, far greater eternal benefits.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>May we have the right perspective and see that serving Yahweh is not only worth whatever we give up and go through in this life, but is the only way to have true joy and peace in this life and the next.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Is It Right to Download YouTube Videos?</title><link>https://noahrahm.com/posts/is-it-right-to-download-youtube-videos/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://noahrahm.com/posts/is-it-right-to-download-youtube-videos/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="why-the-question">Why the question?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>With how popular YouTube is, chances are you either had this question cross your mind or didn&amp;rsquo;t even think about it and went to download videos using one of the free &amp;ldquo;YouTube video downloaders&amp;rdquo; available online.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My motivation behind writing this article is to provoke some thought on this topic as well as just in general about the ethics of breaking TOS (Terms of Service) agreements, software licenses, or EULAs (End User License Agreements).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Unfortunately, people feel safe doing things that so many others do. However, just because everyone else does it does not necessarily make it right.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="answering-the-question">Answering the question&lt;/h3>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Should we use &amp;ldquo;YouTube video downloaders&amp;rdquo; or other software to download YouTube videos?&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>As far as I am concerned, I believe the answer is a clear &lt;strong>no&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>1. It&amp;rsquo;s against the YouTube Terms of Service (TOS)&lt;/strong> to download content outside of the player or download links they provide (more on that later). You agreed to these terms when you created the account, so I mean, that&amp;rsquo;s basically lying if you had no intent to abide by the terms.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/t/terms#c3e2907ca8">YouTube TOS&lt;/a> states:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>You are not allowed to [&amp;hellip;] access, reproduce, download, distribute, transmit, broadcast, display, sell, license, alter, modify or otherwise use any part of the Service or any Content except: (a) as expressly authorized by the Service; or (b) with prior written permission from YouTube and, if applicable, the respective rights holders.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>2. The ads on these third-party YouTube video downloader sites are often malicious&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve watched as someone used one of these sites (against my advice), where halfway through the download, a popup appeared with a download button to download malicious software. You could easily think that the popup was the download for your video, when it wasn&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Many of the ads are just downright deceptive and immoral, which shows the sort of character the people running these sites have.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="what-is-our-standard">What is our standard?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>I used to download videos from YouTube using external software for offline viewing, before I knew that it was a violation of the YouTube TOS. However, ignorance isn&amp;rsquo;t much of an excuse and I no longer do so.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I think about how, if I am willing to break the TOS to download a video from YouTube, then what keeps me from doing anything else against the terms?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In another sense, being a software developer that creates software and website licenses and terms myself, I have to ask myself another question.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>If I am willing to disregard the terms of other websites, then how can I expect &lt;em>others&lt;/em> to abide by the terms or license I create for a website or software?&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>That would be hypocritical.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="video-copyright">Video copyright&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>There is also copyright to think about. The video creators give YouTube a license to show the content through the platform, but that does not automatically give you the right to use or watch the video outside of the platform.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As a video creator on YouTube myself, I think about how I feel about people downloading my videos without my permission and against YouTube&amp;rsquo;s TOC.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s not a good feeling.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="its-not-illegal-or-is-it">It&amp;rsquo;s not &amp;ldquo;illegal&amp;rdquo;. Or is it?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Now, I&amp;rsquo;ve seen other articles and videos where people will say that downloading a video against the terms isn&amp;rsquo;t &amp;ldquo;illegal&amp;rdquo; in some cases, so it&amp;rsquo;s fine. However, YouTube could suspend your account and sue you for breaching their TOS.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>YouTube has tried to take down these external download sites, but it seems they don&amp;rsquo;t because its too much hassle. Too many people download videos using these external sites, and YouTube has never actually sued anyone for downloading content.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That said, this article is not about what is legal or illegal in the sense of what you can get away with. This is about whether it&amp;rsquo;s really right to download videos from YouTube using these external sites.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="so-is-it-right">So, is it right?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>I think sometimes we get lazy and careless, especially if we don&amp;rsquo;t think something will be enforced. However, what&amp;rsquo;s wrong is still wrong, even if you don&amp;rsquo;t see the consequences right away or at all.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ultimately, if you&amp;rsquo;re a believer, what others do is of no consequence. Just because so many people do it and get away with it doesn&amp;rsquo;t make it okay. Is it right according to Scripture? That is the question.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>From what I can see, just the fact that you have to break your word to disregard the YouTube terms of service in order to download videos from YouTube using external sites gives a really clear clue.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;You shall not follow a crowd to do evil.&amp;rdquo; -Exodus 23:2a&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Lying lips are an abomination to Yahweh, But those who deal truthfully are His delight.&amp;rdquo;&amp;quot; -Proverbs 12:22&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Do not lie to one another, since you have put off the old man with his deeds.&amp;rdquo; -Colossians 3:9&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h4 id="an-example-to-illustrate">An example to illustrate&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Imagine you have a rental room at your house.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now, you set certain rules that they must abide by during their stay, one of which is that anything in the room (towels, the mirror, the lamp, etc.) must stay in the room. Imagine them, right after agreeing to the rules, taking your stuff outside for one reason or another and saying, &amp;ldquo;Well, everyone else does it&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I think we would all feel disrespected by the guest.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, if you download videos from YouTube using these external sites, &lt;em>especially&lt;/em> if you don&amp;rsquo;t have permission from the creator, then you are not just disrespecting the platform but the creator too.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="is-it-ever-right-then">Is it ever right, then?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>So, is there ever a time when it would be okay to download a video from YouTube using external sites?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Some people will point to CC (Creative Commons) licensed content or content where the creator says that users are free to download the video if they want.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The problem is that it&amp;rsquo;s still a violation of the YouTube TOS.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I once had a client that had two YouTube channels and wanted to combine them into one. One of the channels only had one video. However, they had forgotten their login information for the account. So they couldn&amp;rsquo;t just download the video through YouTube Studio and reupload it to the other channel.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There was the temptation to just use an external YouTube downloader to retrieve the video. After all, it was &lt;em>his video&lt;/em>, right? It even had his name in the video title.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, we both agreed that it wasn&amp;rsquo;t even an option to violate the TOS by doing so. Instead, I linked to the single video, and that worked just fine.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="ethical-legal-alternatives">Ethical, Legal Alternatives&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Now, you&amp;rsquo;re probably wondering, &amp;ldquo;So what should I do if I&amp;rsquo;m on a limited data plan or want to watch videos offline for another reason?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I see two ways someone could legally and ethically download a YouTube video:&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="youtube-premium">YouTube Premium&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>It appears YouTube allows downloading videos for offline viewing with YouTube Premium. This is what the &amp;ldquo;links that they provide&amp;rdquo; exception in the TOS refers to. Now, I&amp;rsquo;ve never had Premium myself but it is an option to consider if you are wanting offline videos.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="ask-the-creator-directly">Ask the creator directly&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Yes, it&amp;rsquo;s a hassle, but just ask the creator to give you a link to the video on Google Drive, Dropbox, or another file sharing service.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This may actually be an even better option than YouTube Premium since you totally bypass any involvement of YouTube, acknowledge the creator, and get their direct permission to download their content. Now, obviously, the creator is not always going to accept your request. They may say &amp;ldquo;no&amp;rdquo; for one reason or another, and that is understandable.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Other creators may already have a way for you to download their videos offline, though sometimes it is only via a paywall.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="conclusion">Conclusion&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>I think it is pretty clear that we should not be downloading videos from YouTube in ways that violate the YouTube TOS. Instead, we should be respectful of the platform and the creators and either subscribe to YouTube Premium or ask the creator for their video directly.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In a broader sense, I believe we should be careful to abide by whatever agreements we make, whether it&amp;rsquo;s with the software on your PC, a streaming platform like YouTube, or your next-door neighbor.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Journey Behind Velocity Lapse Part 3</title><link>https://noahrahm.com/posts/journey-behind-velocity-lapse-part-3/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://noahrahm.com/posts/journey-behind-velocity-lapse-part-3/</guid><description>&lt;p>This is the third post in a series of &amp;ldquo;dev-log&amp;rdquo; posts of my personal journey and learning process of creating &lt;a href="https://velocitylapse.com">Velocity Lapse&lt;/a>, a time lapse app for Android.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can read the previous posts, &lt;a href="https://noahrahm.com/posts/journey-behind-velocity-lapse-part-1/">Part 1&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://noahrahm.com/posts/journey-behind-velocity-lapse-part-2/">Part 2&lt;/a> to get context up to this point.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="full-rollout-to-open-testing">Full rollout to open testing&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Towards the end of Roman October 2022, I rolled out the app in open testing to all countries where Google Play is available. Previously, it had only been available in 27 select countries because I wanted to make sure to iron out some issues and &amp;ldquo;test the waters&amp;rdquo; so-to-speak before opening up to the whole world.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="first-sales-of-velocity-lapse-pro">First sales of Velocity Lapse PRO&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Roughly a week later, the very first Velocity Lapse PRO upgrade was purchased. Oct. 24th, 2022 to be exact. There were 321 total downloads and 131 active installs at that time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Granted, it was only a few dollars after taxes and Google Play&amp;rsquo;s cut, but it felt really good to have the first sale of the PRO upgrade after months of work with no ROI (besides some nice compliments).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the following weeks, sales happened sporadically, mostly in bunches. There was a total of 8 upgrades in the first 3 weeks of being rolled out to all countries.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="creating-the-first-tutorial">Creating the first tutorial&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>For a while, I had been considering making a tutorial on how to capture a starry night time lapse using Velocity Lapse on an Android phone.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Finally, I took advantage of a night at a campground where I could capture a timelapse of the stars without a lot of light pollution.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The timelapse itself turned out, but I made the mistake of not explaining what I was doing for the tutorial as I was setting up and capturing. Having to voice over the screencapture and time things correctly in the editing stage was a whole lot more work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Although I have created videos before, this was actually my first video tutorial for YouTube that I voiced-over. Even though I felt that it wasn&amp;rsquo;t the best, I was motivated to finish the tutorial because by just finishing it, I knew I would learn something.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As expected, the video didn&amp;rsquo;t get a lot of reception. However, I did learn some important lessons by making the video which I can apply to future videos.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="amazon-app-store">Amazon app store&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>I considered submitting to the Amazon appstore to gain more visibility and to see if I can&amp;rsquo;t submit an app there, even just for the experience.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I created an Amazon developers account and began to go through the form to submit Velocity Lapse so that I could integrate amazon billing into the app. (App stores require you to upload the app bundle before you can create IAP to integrate them into your app).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, after uploading the bundle I found out that due to Velocity Lapse needing the camera autofocus feature, only 3 (old) Amazon devices would be supported. And, at that I would have to lower the minimum SDK version to even get that support.&lt;/p>
&lt;figure>&lt;img src="https://noahrahm.com/posts/journey-behind-velocity-lapse-3/amazon-appstore-app-support.jpg"
alt="A screenshot showing Amazon tablets support for Velocity Lapse"/>&lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Amazon device support for Velocity Lapse&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>So, it just didn&amp;rsquo;t seem worth it. At least, for now.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="social-media-marketing">Social media marketing&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>I finally posted on Instagram. I thought maybe the starscape time lapse video from the tutorial would be a good first post. Got some response.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Youtube channel continued to grow with 40K views on the starry night sky video and a couple hundred views on other videos. I continued to post new time lapse videos roughly every 2 weeks and that caused the channel to gain more subscribers and views.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="product-hunt">Product hunt&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>For quite a while now, I&amp;rsquo;ve eyed &lt;a href="https://producthunt.com">Product Hunt&lt;/a>. I setup the information for Velocity Lapse. However, I could do much more because at this point I didn&amp;rsquo;t have a good idea of when I planned to launch.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="first-negative-reviews">First negative reviews&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Up until this point, there was 99% positive feedback. However, there was a period where a few users submitted 2 bad 1 star reviews through the Google Play testing feedback. Naturally I expected it, just didn&amp;rsquo;t know when it would come.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It appeared that it was due to a bug where the app would crash if the export button was tapped multiple times. So, I had to de bounce the export button to fix the issue.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Or, so I thought.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Obviously, that was &lt;em>an&lt;/em> issue, but it was not &lt;em>the&lt;/em> issue as I continued to recieve feedback that the export didn&amp;rsquo;t work on certain devices.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="crash-analytics">Crash analytics?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Unfortunately, without crash analytics the only thing I had to reference was the Google Play crash reports. By default Google Play just shows that a crash happened, the device, and the exception name.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It made me consider that I may have to give in on my idea of &amp;ldquo;staying away from adding any tracking whatsoever to Velocity Lapse&amp;rdquo;. This was tough, because I really wanted to have no analytics, but without it, is is harder to debug problems users are having with the app.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the end, I decided to hold off on adding analytics and see if I couldn&amp;rsquo;t just figure out the issue myself.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="submitting-to-alternativetonet">Submitting to AlternativeTo.net&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>I submitted Velocity Lapse to &lt;a href="https://alternativeto.net">AlternativeTo.net&lt;/a>, a popular place to look for alternatives to software. In the past, when I&amp;rsquo;ve posted other open source software projects I&amp;rsquo;ve worked on there, a large portion of traffic came from there. So I thought I would try posting Velocity Lapse there for more exposure.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="updating-google-play-and-website">Updating Google Play and website&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Yet again, I updated the website and the Google Play listing to better match the style I came up with while creating promo images for Product Hunt.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="more-woes-of-the-camera2-api">More woes of the camera2 api&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>I have respect for every app developer that deals with camera2 and indeed timelapse app devs. &lt;em>sigh&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One issue I had when previously implementing manual camera controls was with white balance. For some reason, manual white balance wouldn&amp;rsquo;t switch back to auto unless ISO and shutter speed were also auto.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thus, rather than releasing a feature that only partly worked, I just didn&amp;rsquo;t include manual white balance control.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="when-to-release-into-production">When to release into production?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>I needed to make the decision of when to fully release Velocity Lapse. It is tricky because you don&amp;rsquo;t want to release it before it&amp;rsquo;s ready, but you also don&amp;rsquo;t want to overthink it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My thought was to release it early Spring, as the majority of people will likely want to create time lapse videos in the Spring/Summer. So, my strategy was: get the app up to speed during the winter and release somewhere early Spring.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="app-marketing-strategies">App marketing strategies&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The balance between building a great product and marketing is difficult. On one side you want to make the product worthwhile and the best it can be but on the other hand, it&amp;rsquo;s pointless unless someone knows about it. Perfecting the little details while neglected marketing is an easy thing to do.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="heading">&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>I mentioned this in the &lt;a href="https://noahrahm.com/posts/journey-behind-velocity-lapse-part-1/">first post&lt;/a> of this series, but early on when I first started designing the app, I came across something profound.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=pfzxL9lXSdE">this video&lt;/a> about app marketing strategies, he explains a few points which I think are worth sharing here.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The first one is, of course: &lt;strong>Make the app &amp;lsquo;great&amp;rsquo;. Because a &amp;ldquo;just okay&amp;rdquo; app is hard to market.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In order for an app to be successful, it should be something you are proud of, something you (would) use everyday. It should be a legacy, your &amp;ldquo;life&amp;rsquo;s work&amp;rdquo;, something you tell your grandchildren about.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Another words, the app really &lt;em>is&lt;/em> great.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>His second point was: &lt;strong>Reach out to the leading experts (influencers) in your niche and get them to try your app.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It made me think of the fact that if you don&amp;rsquo;t even have the confidence to reach out to leading experts in the niche, your app may not be &amp;lsquo;great&amp;rsquo;. Though, you only have one chance to make a good first impression so you want to make sure you actually do have a &amp;lsquo;great&amp;rsquo; app.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The third point was to: &lt;strong>Build around your core audience&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Getting in close contact with the people that use your app everyday and getting them involved in the building of the app.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I can really say that where I have put these points into practice so far, it has paid off.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="continued-development">Continued development&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>As I winded down the v0.2.x and moved to the v0.3.x series of open testing releases, I planned the roadmap for the next series of releases, v0.3.x and v0.4.x.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="v03x-series">v0.3.x series&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>v0.3.0 was an update I had been planning for a while. I planned to begin implementing the edit view features like importing external images &lt;em>into&lt;/em> an existing project, and (of course) crush some bugs that had been reported.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I rewrote and improved the whole import system, added the ability to import images into an existing project. Thankfully, I was able to fixed some bugs including a long standing bug where images with uppercase file extensions would be ignored when importing.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="beginning-work-on-edit-preview">Beginning work on edit preview&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>I then began working on the preview for the edit view. This required the preview to update quickly when an adjustment was made, so I quickly ruled out using a temporary physical file.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Due to my lack of experience with this side of Flutter, I went ahead and asked in the Flutter help channel about what the most optimized way of creating a real-time image preview was.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It was suggested that I look into the Flutter &lt;code>Texture&lt;/code> widget as that would give me the low-level access to get the update speed I was looking for.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>EDIT: I ended up just leaving off working on this to work on higher priority issues and features&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="user-support">User Support&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>One thing about selling software is the support aspect of it. From the very start, I made a real effort to respond to &lt;em>every&lt;/em> person that submitted feedback on Velocity Lapse, whether good or bad. Many people responded that they appreciated the response which was encouraging.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, I won&amp;rsquo;t lie and say that it was easy to stay on top of it. I took the approach of &amp;ldquo;better late than never&amp;rdquo; when worst came to worst when I didn&amp;rsquo;t get to responding for 2-3 weeks. :(&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="ending-2022">Ending 2022&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>All in all, the first 5 months since I first had the idea for Velocity Lapse have went well.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="app-statistics">App Statistics&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>From a statistical point of view, the app had been growing at a constant rate, gaining anywhere from 10-80 users daily on average.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As of Dec. 31st 2022, there were 914 current installs and just shy of 4K total downloads.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the first 3 months of having the PRO upgrade, the app averaged $35 per month gross. Which, isn&amp;rsquo;t too terrible in my opinion, for an app that is still in early-access and hasn&amp;rsquo;t been heavily promoted yet.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That said, if my main goal was to be making any sort of meaningful revenue from the app, thus far I would be disappointed.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="user-feedback">User feedback&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>I received a good amount of positive feedback. It seemed that the negative feedback came as a result of app crashes, bugs, etc which is totally understandable. I was thankful for everyone that submitted feedback, whether positive or negative, as it helped to gauge the app progress, etc.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="personal-goals">Personal goals&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Thus far, Velocity Lapse is very much usable for creating time lapses. However, I still have a few personal feature needs that I believe need to be implemented. The camera and editor features, motion blur, and star trails are some big ones that I feel are missing. I hope that I can find the time to bring these features into the app in the coming months and years.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, going from not knowing Flutter and not much about Android development, to having an app in beta bringing some ROI and good feedback, I feel that I have learned a lot. It most certainly has been a journey of overcoming challenges, both technical and physical.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="the-journey-continues">The journey continues&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Thanks for reading. I hope you&amp;rsquo;ve enjoyed this post and have gained something from this journey so far. I know I have.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you have a suggestion, a comment or some advice, relating either to the app or this post, I&amp;rsquo;d love to hear what you have to share either in the comments below or via &lt;a href="mailto:hi@noahrahm.com">email&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>You can read the next part of the journey in &lt;a href="https://noahrahm.com/posts/journey-behind-velocity-lapse-part-4/">part 4&lt;/a> of this series.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>&lt;em>A big thanks to numerous individuals for their support and advice, making this journey possible. Special thanks to &lt;a href="https://github.com/sundrycode">@sundrycode&lt;/a> for which I am grateful for his help developing the Android native side of the app and taking part in testing. And Yahweh, our Heavenly Father from whom all knowledge and every good thing comes.&lt;/em>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Life Lessons from 2022</title><link>https://noahrahm.com/posts/life-lessons-2022/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://noahrahm.com/posts/life-lessons-2022/</guid><description>&lt;p>In the past year I&amp;rsquo;ve made a greater effort to look for what Yahweh, our Heavenly Father, is try to show me in every situation. There is always something to learn, even in the darkest of situations. :)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Life is a journey. A believer&amp;rsquo;s life is continuing to grow in Yahushua (commonly called &amp;ldquo;Jesus&amp;rdquo;). It is following the footsteps of the Savior. Learning little, by little.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ll say that it is much easier to learn the lessons He is trying to teach you the first time. Though, if you don&amp;rsquo;t stop to think about what He is showing you, then you probably won&amp;rsquo;t learn it.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="lessons">Lessons&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>So, here is my reflection of life lessons that stand out the most from what I&amp;rsquo;ve learned this past year. I&amp;rsquo;ve intentionally left these rather general so that you can see how these can apply in difference circumstances.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="precedence">Precedence&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Things need to be Yahweh&amp;rsquo;s way from the very start, to begin with. The first meeting of something is probably how the rest will be. First impression &lt;em>is&lt;/em> important. Subsequent meetings will probably follow the same pattern and it is hard to steer it right again.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="confrontation">Confrontation&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>As hard as it is, if you can&amp;rsquo;t overlook something in another believer, you must confront the person and make it right. Follow Matthew 18.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>15&lt;/strong> &amp;ldquo;Moreover if your brother sins against you, go and tell him his fault between you and him alone. If he hears you, you have gained your brother. &lt;strong>16&lt;/strong> But if he will not hear, take with you one or two more, that &amp;lsquo;by the mouth of two or three witnesses every word may be established.&amp;rsquo; &lt;strong>17&lt;/strong> And if he refuses to hear them, tell it to the church. But if he refuses even to hear the church, let him be to you like a heathen and a tax collector.&amp;rdquo; -Matt. 18:15-17&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Don&amp;rsquo;t wait to resolve an issue with someone if it cannot be forgotten. The longer it goes on, the harder it will be to resolve. Glossing over problems and avoiding talking about them &lt;strong>doesn&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/strong> solve the problem.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="expectations">Expectations&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Misunderstandings and conflicts can happen when both parties are not clear on their expectations. Be clear what you expect from others and clarify their expectations of you.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="loyalty">Loyalty&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Remember who you are working for and who your loyalty belongs to. People &lt;strong>will&lt;/strong> fail. People &lt;strong>will&lt;/strong> have conflicts.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Remember that you are not working for men but for Yahweh. Don&amp;rsquo;t be discouraged. Be loyal to Yahweh and the calling &lt;strong>He&lt;/strong> has called you to.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Whatever you do, do your work heartily, as for Yahweh rather than for men&amp;rdquo; -Colossians 3:23&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h4 id="communication">Communication&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Remember that life is about relationships and without communication, there is no relationship.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Never be too busy to listen to others or talk to them, especially if you have a conflict. Remember that it is a two-way street. Both parties need to talk &lt;strong>and&lt;/strong> listen to the other.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Remember that the most important communication is with Yahweh through prayer.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="patience">Patience&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Wait&lt;/strong> for Yahweh&amp;rsquo;s timing and plan. Don&amp;rsquo;t rush ahead without His leading.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Trust in Yahweh with all your heart, And lean not on your own understanding; In all your ways acknowledge Him, And He shall direct your paths.&amp;rdquo; -Proverbs 3:5-6&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>However, don&amp;rsquo;t confuse patience with procrastination(!) or lack of faith.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="judgement">Judgement&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Make sure you hear both sides and have the facts before you judge a matter. Don&amp;rsquo;t be too quick to blame or release from blame.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As hard as it is, wait until you have &lt;strong>all&lt;/strong> of the information about the situation before making a judgement. Don&amp;rsquo;t feel pressured to make a judgement hastily.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="facts">Facts&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Don&amp;rsquo;t assume you have all the facts or think you know something about someone or something. It is easy to be &amp;ldquo;in the moment&amp;rdquo; and end up making up things, assuming things that aren&amp;rsquo;t true.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="self-imposed-rules">Self-Imposed Rules&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Don&amp;rsquo;t seek to establish your &lt;strong>own&lt;/strong> form of righteousness. Study the Scriptures and walk out Yahweh&amp;rsquo;s righteousness. Don&amp;rsquo;t look down on those that do not follow your self-imposed rules, even if they are good, but not necessarily from Scripture.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="appearance">Appearance&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Remember that sometimes people will assume things about you based on &lt;strong>appearance&lt;/strong> or by what you &lt;strong>don&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/strong> say as much as what you do say. Don&amp;rsquo;t take it personally if someone thinks bad of you because of it. Yahweh justifies.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="compromise">Compromise&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Compromising on what Scripture says, even a little bit, opens the door to a continuous erosion of it from your life. Once the door is open, it is hard to close. Be sure that any compromise you make &lt;strong>does not compromise your belief in Yahweh&amp;rsquo;s Word.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="jealousy">Jealousy&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Don&amp;rsquo;t get jealous of other people&amp;rsquo;s situations, etc. Jealousy stems from discontentment. The grass &lt;strong>isn&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/strong> greener on the other side of the fence. &lt;strong>Everyone&lt;/strong> has their own set of problems and they may be worse than yours. Be content where Yahweh has placed you in life.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="be-humble-be-real">Be Humble; Be Real&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Be humble, knowing that you deserve death, but Yahweh showed you mercy and grace. Show the same mercy and grace that He shows to &lt;strong>You&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Do not look down on others for what you &lt;strong>think&lt;/strong> they do not know or practice. You also have things that Yahweh is trying to get your attention about and you must be humble to even see what He is trying to teach you.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Everyone&lt;/strong> has problems and struggles they deal with. Don&amp;rsquo;t act like you have everything together when it is not the case. Even people, in general, will appreciate your honesty in admitting that you have struggles over acting like you have it all together.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="conclusion">Conclusion&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>I hope this post has blessed and encouraged you. If you would like to share life lessons &lt;strong>you&lt;/strong> have learned this past year, I would love to hear what they are in the comments below.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Journey Behind Velocity Lapse Part 2</title><link>https://noahrahm.com/posts/journey-behind-velocity-lapse-part-2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://noahrahm.com/posts/journey-behind-velocity-lapse-part-2/</guid><description>&lt;p>In &lt;a href="https://noahrahm.com/posts/journey-behind-velocity-lapse-part-1/">Part 1&lt;/a>, I shared the &amp;ldquo;journey&amp;rdquo; of creating &lt;a href="https://velocitylapse.com">Velocity Lapse&lt;/a> (a time lapse app for Android), up to the first internal testing release.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="technical-setbacks">Technical setbacks&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>If I&amp;rsquo;ve made it seem like development was easy with only a few snags in the previous post, then let me reassure you that it wasn&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="why-i-am-sharing-technical-issues">Why I am sharing technical issues&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>It would take a while to relate to you all of the technical challenges I encountered. I also don&amp;rsquo;t want to make this into a series of posts relating every problem I&amp;rsquo;ve had!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, I think it&amp;rsquo;s worth briefly mentioning some of them so that someone can learn and benefit from my mistakes and research.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="resolving-a-limitation-of-the-official-camera-package">Resolving a limitation of the official camera package&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Since I was using a fork of the official Flutter camera package, the maximum capture resolution was determined by the video capture resolution supported by the device hardware.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It seems that someone else had come across this limitation as well and had created a fork with some patch code. I was able to adapt the code to allow capturing 4K (if supported) and the full camera sensor resolution.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="another-encoder-issue">Another encoder issue&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>As it would be, though, resolving that limitation led to uncovering something else.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When exporting a video with a resolution higher than the supported video capture resolution, the encoder would crash with a null pointer exception.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So, more issues with the encoder but this time relating to the video encoding resolution.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thankfully, &lt;a href="https://github.com/sundrycode">@sundrycode&lt;/a> graciously helped out with his Android development experience.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After we both did a ridiculous amount of online searching going down multiple rabbit trails and to old and obscure websites on the MediaCodec API, we came to a conclusion that seems logical.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It appears that the device encoding resolution implementation for the MediaCodec api is determined by the supported &lt;em>video capture&lt;/em> resolution. Therefore, encoding a 4K video isn&amp;rsquo;t going to be supported on a device that only supports HD video. For most new but cheap Android phones, the video capture resolution is 1080p HD (1920x1080).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Indeed it is a hunch, but it seems to be confirmable and logical. If you know for certain please let me know in the comments below.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="first-open-testing-release">First open testing release&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Getting to the point where I figured the app was stable enough for open testing (also known as &amp;ldquo;early access&amp;rdquo;) took 4 months of work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In order to submit Velocity Lapse to Google Play for review, I went through the process of writing a description, creating a feature image, and capturing and editing screenshots for the app store page.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I wrote the description highlighing the main features and the fact that Velocity Lapse captures images rather than capturing straight to video. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t a great description, but it did the job.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After submitting, I didn&amp;rsquo;t waste time waiting around for the review to go through. The release was another milestone in my journey, but the app still needed a lot of work before it could really be a great app and something someone would pay for.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="why-i-wont-use-stock-images-to-promote-velocity-lapse">Why I won&amp;rsquo;t use stock images to promote Velocity Lapse&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>One thing to note is that I&amp;rsquo;ve committed to only displaying images and screenshots on the listing and website that were &lt;strong>actually&lt;/strong> captured using Velocity Lapse on a mobile device.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What do I mean? Well, I won&amp;rsquo;t be showcasing Velocity Lapse using stock photography or other images &lt;em>not&lt;/em> captured with the Velocity Lapse (unless it is clear that the images are externally captured).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You may be surprised, but sadly it is not uncommon for even well-known apps - even some &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VLKvg8a6g4E">mobile camera apps&lt;/a> - to use stock photography for the app store listing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now, for some apps I think that it is fine to use stock photography, such as photo editors. There&amp;rsquo;s nothing to say what camera took the image.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, for an app where the camera functionality is a big feature (or, &lt;em>gasp&lt;/em> -the main feature!), the best way to showcase the app is by displaying images that it captured. Anything else would seem to be deceptive and/or misleading in my mind.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Although using images that were actually captured with the app can mean that there isn&amp;rsquo;t as much variety and/or it doesn&amp;rsquo;t look as good, it does give the viewer an accurate idea of what to expect. Thus, it keeps their expectations in-line with reality.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="promotion-and-my-social-media-strategy">Promotion and my social media strategy&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>One idea which &lt;a href="https://github.com/sundrycode">@sundrycode&lt;/a> and a few others suggested, was to post timelapse videos created with Velocity Lapse.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The thought was that maybe if the videos got popular enough, they would promote the app and inspire others to create their own. They would also serve as real-life examples of what can be created with Velocity Lapse.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So, I created a &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCenuOeODNjdVohMTvKv15fQ">Youtube channel&lt;/a> and began posting time lapse videos there. I also created an &lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/velocitylapseapp/">Instagram account&lt;/a>, but it sat there unused for a few months, until I got around to making content to post there.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In addition, I did quite a bit of posting on Reddit. Mostly just replying to existing posts looking for a time lapse app. Since the OP was asking for time lapse apps and those viewing the post were likely looking as well, it was a good way to get some first users and help them find something they could use to create time lapses.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All in all, this was a pretty good strategy looking back at the successes in both avenues.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="user-testing-and-the-interface-refactoring-loop">User testing and the interface refactoring loop&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>After yet more user testing and feedback, I began a refactoring of the UI. At first, it primarily centered around the home view.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The most useful method of conducting user testing that I have found is physically watching the test users use the app. I mean practically looking over their shoulder and writing down notes about their interaction.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Getting face-to-face feedback, both positive and negative and seeing how people use the app in real life crushes some dreamy, false notions you can have as a developer/designer about how the app should work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Getting this feedback at this point brought up some good ideas for improvements as well as confirmed some ideas that I was personally hesitant to implement (I&amp;rsquo;ll admit).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It was without doubt a popular request to add a gallery to view exported videos, so I added it to the near future roadmap. I also moved the main call to action buttons to a more thumb friendly position and polished up various parts of the UI.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="introduction-of-the-bottom-nagivation-bar">Introduction of the bottom nagivation bar&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>In order to better organize the new features such as importing a sequence of images as a project, I introduced a bottom navigation bar. It divided Velocity Lapse&amp;rsquo;s main functions into three understandable categories.&lt;/p>
&lt;figure>&lt;img src="https://noahrahm.com/posts/journey-behind-velocity-lapse-2/bottom-navigation-bar.jpg"
alt="Bottom navigation"/>&lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Introducing the bottom tab navigation&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;h3 id="the-second-open-testing-release">The second open testing release&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>With the new &amp;ldquo;import images as a project&amp;rdquo; feature and the UI refactor, I was eager to publish and roll out another release.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thankfully, by the time I had the release ready a week later, the Google Play app review went through and Velocity Lapse was finally published for public, early access.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="third-open-testing-release">Third open testing release&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The third open testing release included the new tab navigation and the &amp;ldquo;import images as project&amp;rdquo; feature.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I now felt like promoting a bit so I updated the website and replied to a few questions asking for time lapse app suggestions on Reddit. It turned out to be a good thing as over the next few months, a couple of people found Velocity Lapse through my comment and gave feedback.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="focusing-on-the-things-users-care-about">Focusing on the things users care about&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Listening and acting upon user feedback can be hard. For Velocity Lapse, the feedback was mainly concerning missing features.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As a designer and developer that also has a tendency to be a pefectionist, it can be very easy to prioritize the things I care about (a clean, sleek interface and well-written code) rather than the things end users actually care about (like feature X or Y).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I was reminded that tweaking the UI is great, but ultimately most users will accept the way that it is. They &lt;em>will&lt;/em> care whether a certain feature is available and works. So, I need to focus on &lt;em>functional&lt;/em> features that meet the needs of the user.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Working on &amp;ldquo;fun&amp;rdquo; parts that I like is great, but if in the end users don&amp;rsquo;t ever need it, then it is a waste of time.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="adding-manual-capture-mode">Adding Manual Capture mode&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The capture view with the interval setting and other features was great, however it didn&amp;rsquo;t fulfill one required use-case that I had in mind from the beginning: time lapse captures over &lt;em>extended periods of time&lt;/em>. It would also catering to those who would rather not leave their device somewhere while it is capturing.&lt;/p>
&lt;figure>&lt;img src="https://noahrahm.com/posts/journey-behind-velocity-lapse-2/manual-capture-view.jpg"
alt="Manual capture view"/>&lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>The manual capture view in v0.0.4+6&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>I named this mode, the Manual Capture mode. It includes a camera view with an overlay of the previous image and an indicator telling when the last image was captured.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This was simple enough to implement, but it still took time to differentiate the project UI from the normal Timelapse capture mode and develop the special interface for it.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="first-submitted-feedback">First submitted feedback&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>After nine versions released into early access, I felt more confident about Velocity Lapse. It had come aways since the first version, going from a barely useable app to an app I actually wanted and enjoyed using almost everyday.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At this point, I updated the website landing page to better showcase the app and direct visitors to Google Play.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Not long after, I received the first externally submitted feedback on Velocity Lapse. It included a crash report and a few suggestions on how to make the import images as projects feature more user-friendly.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="monitizing-the-app">Monitizing the app&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>If I was creating a free app, the main work would be complete. However, because this is an app with IAPs (in-app purchases), it required the steps to integrate with Google Play billing. This turned out to be one of more challenging parts of creating Velocity Lapse thus far.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="the-question-of-app-monitization">The question of app monitization&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>There was one thing I was not confident about, and that is what features to have as in-app purchases for the PRO version.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I settled upon having the free version limited in the following ways:&lt;/p>
&lt;h6 id="free-version">FREE VERSION&lt;/h6>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Limit of up to 5 projects at one time&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Export up to 1080p video&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Import images as project limited to import of 400 images&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h6 id="pro-version">PRO VERSION&lt;/h6>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Unlock unlimited projects&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Export up to 4K video (if the device supports it)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Import images as project with unlimited number of images&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>This way, the free version of the app is limited in a way that all the features are usable, but there is (hopefully) enough of an incentive to upgrade to the PRO version to allow unlimited access.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="keeping-the-sabbath-day">Keeping the Sabbath day&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Something that I wanted to make sure to do, was block purchasing Velocity Lapse PRO on Saturday, in observance of the Sabbath day.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I believe in keeping the seventh day Sabbath (Roman Saturday) as described in the Bible. The Sabbath is a set-apart day of rest and so no buying, selling, or trading is to be done on it (as I understand it).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ll state here that I am &lt;strong>not&lt;/strong> a part of any demonination (SDA or otherwise).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My motivation for keeping the Sabbath holy is to do as Yahweh, our Heavenly Father Himself, and our Savior did: rest on the seventh day.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;And on the seventh day Yahweh ended his work which he had made; and he rested on the seventh day from all his work which he had made. And Yahweh blessed the seventh day, and sanctified it: because that in it he had rested from all his work which Yahweh created and made.&amp;rdquo; -Genesis 2:2-3&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;If thou turn away thy foot from the sabbath, from doing thy pleasure on My holy day; and call the sabbath a delight, the holy of Yahweh, honourable; and shalt honour him, not doing thine own ways, nor finding thine own pleasure, nor speaking thine own words: Then shalt thou delight thyself in Yahweh; and I will cause thee to ride upon the high places of the earth, and feed thee with the heritage of Jacob thy father: for the mouth of Yahweh hath spoken it.&amp;rdquo; -Isaiah 58:13-14&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>There are many more verses in the Bible regarding the importance of keeping the seventh day Sabbath.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For some Django-based websites I worked on in the past, I had created and used a Django app called &lt;a href="https://github.com/Correct-Syntax/Keep-Sabbath">Keep Sabbath&lt;/a> which would redirect visitors, or show a banner stating that the e-commerce site was closed for the Sabbath day.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I did something similar for Velocity Lapse, so that a screen would come up letting them know that they wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be able to purchase until the next day.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The saying, &lt;em>&amp;ldquo;A day of rest, a Sabbath request: please refrain from purchasing between sundown Friday and sundown Saturday.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em> was inspired by someone else&amp;rsquo;s banner I had seen.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="technical-implementation-of-iap">Technical implementation of IAP&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Creating the PRO upgrade screen UI itself was one of the screen I most enjoyed implementing (for whatever reason).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, implementing the IAP integration itself proved to be a lengthy process.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I decided to use &lt;a href="https://revenuecat.com">RevenueCat&lt;/a> to manage purchase validation, etc. rather than writing and maintaining my own web API to do so.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Setting up a Google cloud service account and connecting it to RevenueCat for accessing the Play Store API on my behalf was a lengthy, but necessary process.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Unfortunately, not everything in the docs for Flutter RevenueCat integration was as clear as I thought it should be.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The main culprit of the problems was Dart null safety. Many articles online didn&amp;rsquo;t handle null safety, and the snippets in the RevenueCat docs only went so far. For that reason, I may write a post in the future on how to implement RevenueCat with Flutter and Dart null safety.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thankfully, I was familiar enough with Dart to figure it out. In the end, I had a single in-app purchase for users to upgrade to Velocity Lapse PRO for $3.99 USD.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="updating-the-google-play-listing-again">Updating the Google Play listing (again)&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Now that we had a pretty solid version of Velocity Lapse, I went and captured updated screenshots of major screens of the app and created phone screenshots for the Google Play listing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This time, I used a different style with a faded image behind the phone and screenshot mockup as well as a horizontal screenshot to better showcase the two capture modes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For the months prior, I had been posting some of the timelapse videos I had captured to the official Velocity Lapse YouTube channel. I added one of the videos as the &amp;ldquo;feature video&amp;rdquo; for Google Play. In my opinion, just adding the video made the listing look a lot better than before.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="posting-on-reddit">Posting on Reddit&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>I submitted a &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/androidapps/comments/xjve1u/velocity_lapse_create_your_own_time_lapse_videos/">Reddit post&lt;/a> to gather feedback regarding Velocity Lapse. The post received 700+ views in the first week. It caused a surge of downloads and I did recieve some helpful feedback (albeit, not on Reddit itself).&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="big-features-big-holdups">Big features, big holdups&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The next tasks on the roadmap were to get 4k export and manual camera controls implemented.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="4k-video-export">4K video export&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>4k export to video wasn&amp;rsquo;t a huge feature to implement. However, since I didn&amp;rsquo;t have an Android device that supported 4k, it made testing tricky. I ended up getting an hour to test on a friend&amp;rsquo;s phone which I hoped was enough to have caught any issues.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If not&amp;hellip; I was sure users would let me know.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>EDIT:&lt;/strong> they did.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h4 id="manual-camera-controls">Manual camera controls&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>I spent two weeks working through the Android camera2 API to implement manual camera controls, ISO, shutter speed and focus distance (manual focus).&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="the-woes-of-the-camera2-api">The woes of the camera2 API&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Needless to say, working with the Android camera2 API was not easy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Something that worked on one device didn&amp;rsquo;t on another, which lends to the reason it is &lt;a href="https://www.androidpolice.com/why-third-party-camera-apps-are-so-bad-on-android/">notorious&lt;/a> for fragmented support and overall a bad experience for developers. So much so that some app developers &lt;a href="https://9to5google.com/2020/02/29/moment-pro-camera-app-android-exclusive/">give up on it&lt;/a>. Which, makes me feel uneasy and sort of mad.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The first time I tried to capture a night timelapse of the stars, it didn&amp;rsquo;t turn out as I expected. I had been working on implementing shutter speed and ISO controls which would allow for night captures.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I set the device out to capture and it seemed perfect in the camera preview. However, when came back and looked at the captured images afterwards, I realized that images were being captured as if auto exposure was still on.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Finally after two weeks of researching and testing to get manual camera controls implemented correctly, I finally got the code to a point where it worked.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I tried capturing a starry night timelapse once again. I pointed the device upwards, set the shutter speed to 1 sec and the ISO to 6400, then left it to time lapse for ~2 hours. The result was satisfying for a first successful attempt.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I was happy to post the video on YouTube since it was the first night timelapse that had turned out fairly nicely.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="some-encouragement-via-positive-feedback">Some encouragement via positive feedback&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Thankfully, it was now working and more users and positive feedback came as a result of my posts on Reddit, which was encouraging. Nicely timed it was, as one person suggested that I add manual camera controls!&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="turning-the-landing-page-into-a-website">Turning the landing page into a website&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>I finally took some time aside to create a decent design for &lt;a href="https://velocitylapse.com">the website&lt;/a> that would showcase the app features and the timelapses that I had captured with it. My main thought with it was to inspire people to get out and create their own time lapses.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At this point, there was 97 total app downloads and 40 active installs.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="an-opportunity-to-learn-more-in-depth-about-photography">An opportunity to learn more in-depth about photography&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Essentially, in the process of creating Velocity Lapse&amp;rsquo;s camera features, I&amp;rsquo;m working towards a camera app with extra-nice timelapse functionality. I find that kind of interesting.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What&amp;rsquo;s nice about working on this kind of project that deals with the camera is that its enabled me (maybe &amp;lsquo;given me a good excuse&amp;rsquo; is better wording) to spend time learning about manual camera controls in-depth, professional photography and, of course, time lapse photography.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Had I chosen to work on a project like a file manager, I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have probably ever taken the time to dive into photography as I have now. Needless to say, I don&amp;rsquo;t regret my decision (quite the opposite).&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="an-opportunity-to-enjoy-creation">An opportunity to enjoy creation&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>During the process of creating and testing the app I have had the opportunity to spend more time enjoying creation. Namely, the sky.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Whether it&amp;rsquo;s wispy clouds, or a pink and blue sunset, creating a time lapse app has given me a good excuse to pay attention to it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve really enjoyed it and maybe through creating this app, maybe I can compel and give more people an &amp;ldquo;excuse&amp;rdquo; to get out and enjoy it too.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;div class="youtube-player">
&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/fBrOPxkeTnw" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video">&lt;/iframe>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="youtube-player">
&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/36O4d31UyyE" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video">&lt;/iframe>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So, I encourage you to &lt;a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.velocitylapse.velocitylapse">download the app&lt;/a> and go outside to capture a time lapse yourself. :)&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="the-starry-night-sky-timelapse-video-gets-popular-on-youtube">The starry night sky timelapse video gets popular on Youtube&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Speaking of enjoying creation, it seemed that people enjoyed the starscape time lapse on the Velocity Lapse YouTube channel. The video received 1K views and 11 likes in the first week, &lt;strong>4.7K views and 46 likes in the first 3 weeks&lt;/strong>, and has 6K views and 56 likes as of this writing.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Later update: The video now has &lt;strong>over 83K views&lt;/strong>, which is kind of crazy (to me) for a 30 second video.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;figure>&lt;img src="https://noahrahm.com/posts/journey-behind-velocity-lapse-2/starry-night-sky-analytics-10-2022.jpg"
alt="Starry night sky timelapse video analytics"/>&lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>A glance at the stats for the starry night sky time lapse video on Youtube as of 10/26/22&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>Needless to say, this was way, far better than any other video I posted.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Granted, it was a short video, but it was interesting and new to me especially since other videos on the Velocity Lapse channel had fewer than 100 views (as of this writing).&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="youtube-player">
&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/BxRHqPGGO_g" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video">&lt;/iframe>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>The downloads on Google Play tripled and some feedback and support queries came my way during this time. I assume due to the video receiving so much attention.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oddly enough, this happened while I was away on vacation. Go figure.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="the-journey-continues">The journey continues&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Thanks for reading. I hope you&amp;rsquo;ve enjoyed this post and have gained something from this journey so far. I know I have.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you have a suggestion, a comment or some advice, relating either to the app or this post, I&amp;rsquo;d love to hear what you have to share either in the comments below or via &lt;a href="mailto:hi@noahrahm.com">email&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Read the next part of the journey in &lt;a href="https://noahrahm.com/posts/journey-behind-velocity-lapse-part-3/">part 3&lt;/a> of this series.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>&lt;em>A big thanks to numerous individuals for their support and advice, making this journey possible. Special thanks to &lt;a href="https://github.com/sundrycode">@sundrycode&lt;/a> for which I am grateful for his help developing the Android native side of the app and taking part in testing. And Yahweh, our Heavenly Father from whom all knowledge and every good thing comes.&lt;/em>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Journey Behind Velocity Lapse Part 1</title><link>https://noahrahm.com/posts/journey-behind-velocity-lapse-part-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://noahrahm.com/posts/journey-behind-velocity-lapse-part-1/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="a-new-project">A new project&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on a new side-project for the last few months. It&amp;rsquo;s a new time lapse app for Android called &lt;a href="https://velocitylapse.com">Velocity Lapse&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This post is the start of a series of dev-log posts I&amp;rsquo;m planning to write of my personal journey and learning process of creating Velocity Lapse. I plan to share the steps of planning, UI design, development, launch, and marketing -some of which is the first time I have done so for a mobile app.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Although I am not at all new to design or development, mobile app development is a relatively new area for me. My only experience with mobile app development up to this point are my contributions to &lt;a href="https://biblenotify.github.io">Bible Notify&lt;/a> and some design-related work for another app.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Above that, this the first time I have directly monitized one of my own software projects as I usually go &lt;a href="https://github.com/Correct-Syntax">open-source&lt;/a> for most non-client projects.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That is to say, if you&amp;rsquo;re more experienced in app development or the business side of things (or even if you not) and you have a suggestion, a comment or some advice, I&amp;rsquo;d love to hear what you have to share via &lt;a href="mailto:hi@noahrahm.com">email&lt;/a> or the comments section below.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="the-app-idea">The app idea&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Every good project starts with a good, worthwhile idea.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="initial-ideas">Initial ideas&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Initially, some ideas I thought about were:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>A very reliable writers app where you don&amp;rsquo;t lose your work. (Probably sounds silly, but the existing apps, I&amp;rsquo;m told, don&amp;rsquo;t quite cut it).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>A file manager that could reach the level of the discontinued &amp;ldquo;ES file explorer&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>However, while I do write some and I probably could use a file manager, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t interested in those ideas enough or see enough of a need for them &lt;em>personally&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>While I think it is important to work on projects in areas you are &lt;em>not&lt;/em> really interested in to broaden your skills, I&amp;rsquo;ve found that it is easier to stick with something you are passionate about.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My personal interest are in the areas of: the Bible, graphics, photography, and design -as evidenced by some of &lt;a href="https://github.com/Correct-Syntax">my open source work&lt;/a>. So, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t see myself developing the aforementioned ideas into apps.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="the-final-idea">The final idea&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>With a bit more brainstorming, I came up with the idea of creating an app to create &lt;strong>time lapses&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have fond memories of when I was younger and would experiment with time lapse using an old tablet. My brother and I would time lapse plants growing and mushrooms appearing in our greenhouse.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Time lapse, if you&amp;rsquo;re not aware, is the process of capturing images at intervals slower than a normal video and piecing them together to produce a video that is sped-up/condensed so naturally slow movements appear much faster. The time lapse effect can be very beautiful for things like sunsets, clouds, flowers/plants, or people walking the streets.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="youtube-player">
&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/pi9G6py2Hv0" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video">&lt;/iframe>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>Again, I did some quick validation of the idea from a personal standpoint and realized it was something I could personally use. I could glorify Yahweh (our Heavenly Father) with it by showing the beauty of His Creation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After coming up with the idea, it was time to do some market research.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="make-the-app-great">&amp;ldquo;Make the app great&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Early on, I stumbled upon some advice from someone talking about marketing an app which really struck me. The bit of advice was &lt;strong>&amp;ldquo;make the app great&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Maybe that sounds obvious, but it is way too easy to get the cart ahead of the horse and spend most of the effort marketing the product instead of making the product itself great.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Obviously, that doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean no time should be spent marketing, as that is another trap to fall into. However, as a web developer and designer myself, I know how much easier it is to promote something that is &amp;ldquo;great&amp;rdquo; to start with. I also know how excited I could (personally) get about creating a website to promote it, while neglecting the product itself! You know, sort-of as a way to procrastinate&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So from then on, I decided to have had the mindset of building a user-friendly, user-centric app focused on improving time lapse on Android and &lt;strong>solving the paint-points&lt;/strong> found in other apps. Like, literally making this a &amp;ldquo;great&amp;rdquo; time lapse app.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>From a marketing standpoint, &lt;strong>people buy solutions to their problems, not software.&lt;/strong> So, solving user pain-points is the best approach that I am aware of.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="market-research">Market Research&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>I conducted research on the Google Play store as well as some of the top apps on the Apple App store to get an idea of the current state of time lapse/camera apps for Android and see where the pain points were.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As someone that has always had an interest in photography and videography, I had already used a few of the more well-known Android timelapse apps before I ever had the idea to create one. However, after reading through hundreds of reviews and creating a ton of notes, I could see some areas where the current apps were failing, where they were doing well, and what people were looking for in a time lapse app.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I was also able to get some metrics of apps on the market via Apptopia&amp;rsquo;s free report, which was helpful.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="initial-planning">Initial planning&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s one thing to discover things that could be improved in other apps, it&amp;rsquo;s totally another thing to fix them and pull off a great user experience in your own.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So, why doesn&amp;rsquo;t everyone just go out and make a timelapse app?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It was pretty clear from the amount of notes I had taken that even a simple timelapse app has a lot of things that need to be done just right.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Two things really stood out from my notes:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Reliability&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Flexibility&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Reliability&lt;/strong> because who wants to go through the trouble of setting up a time lapse and waiting for the capture to complete (and for the video to render in some cases) only for the app to crash or something non-intuitive happens? No one, of course.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Flexibility&lt;/strong> because when you go to download an app, it should be capable of doing things in a non-limiting way and respond well under a variety of circumstances.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Wait.&lt;/em> Did I unknowingly just describe a good app in general? ..I guess I have.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Indeed, because having reliability and flexibility is an important part of making good software in general.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="initial-ui-sketches--ideas">Initial UI sketches &amp;amp; ideas&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>I then drew some initial sketches and wrote notes of what I imagined the UI and workflow to be, without diving into other apps, so I could come up with some original ideas.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let me be honest: looking back, those sketches were a bit naive and didn&amp;rsquo;t include some settings a time lapse app should have. (I guess I didn&amp;rsquo;t know about time lapse as deeply as I may have thought). However, it gave me a springboard to where I could get started with my &lt;em>own&lt;/em> take on a time lapse app, even if it was a little out of reality and missing features&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I then opened up to installing and testing almost every app related to time lapse on Google Play over the period of the next month and a half, taking notes and reading reviews to gather what I could. I also did some looking online for independent reviews as well as some apps on the Apple App Store.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Moving to my laptop I then created a digital mock-up of the different screens (views) that the app would have. At this point, I over-complicated it in certain areas like the home screen where I was thinking everything could/should be crammed. Therefore, I did end up going back and recreating the layout a number of times to get it condensed down to a better design.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="my-choice-of-a-tech-stack">My Choice of a Tech Stack&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>For the tech-savy readers (read: developers) the tech stack I chose is pretty simple:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://flutter.dev">Flutter&lt;/a> for the UI&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Dart (because of Flutter) for the main business logic&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Java/Kotlin for any native platform code needed (on Android)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Prior to this I had never done Flutter/Dart development and only had a small bit of Java experience so this was an entirely unfamiliar tech stack to me.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="why-flutterdart">Why Flutter/Dart?&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Why not?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Real answer: Flutter looked really neat, was something I had been wanting to try for a while. It&amp;rsquo;s cross-platform and isn&amp;rsquo;t limited by the performance of a webview/browser engine. In addition, Flutter has hot-reload and really great tooling for Android Studio and VScode.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="why-not-react-native-etc">Why not React Native, etc?&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>I was concerned about the performance of using a js framework. Also didn&amp;rsquo;t feel that using a js framework for an app that accesses so much lower-level hardware (like the camera) was a good idea.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="alright-why-not-native-javakotlin-then">Alright, why not native Java/Kotlin then?&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Besides the comments above, I just haven&amp;rsquo;t liked Java Android development all that much from my bits of working with it. (More just a personal preference.)&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Ironically, I ended up diving into both Java &lt;strong>and&lt;/strong> Kotlin &lt;strong>a lot&lt;/strong>. (What did I expect for an app that accesses so much hardware?!) Thankfully, I had help from &lt;a href="https://github.com/sundrycode">@sundrycode&lt;/a> who has a lot more experience than I with Android development.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h3 id="initial-development-learning-dartflutter">&lt;del>Initial development&lt;/del> Learning Dart/Flutter&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>I was eager to get started with developing the app as I figured there would be a learning phase with Flutter and Dart. I was pleasantly surprised at how simple the installation and project setup was. The default Flutter project code didn&amp;rsquo;t seem too far out either.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="the-first-hurdle-android-emulators">The first hurdle: Android emulators&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>For whatever reason, however, the Android emulators kept giving me issues. The emulators wouldn&amp;rsquo;t restart until after I rebooted my laptop. It ended up being a configuration problem on my end (of course..).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Later on when I needed a more realistic idea of what I was doing, I enabled USB debugging to my Android phone which helped to greatly improve my productivity and testing.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Tip: Make sure your phone&amp;rsquo;s font size is set to &lt;code>Default&lt;/code> when testing otherwise the text scaling could be off and when you install the app on a phone with a larger screen, the UI text could be tiny.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h4 id="the-second-hurdle-flutter-constraints">The second hurdle: Flutter constraints&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Once past the emulators hurdle, I quickly learned that Flutter constraints are &lt;strong>not&lt;/strong> like web layouts.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I kept running into the (in)famous overflow errors and &lt;code>unbounded layout constraints&lt;/code> fatal errors. Needless to say, I didn&amp;rsquo;t get very far until I understood how constraints and layout worked.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It is wise advice to read and understand the Flutter docs on &lt;a href="https://docs.flutter.dev/development/ui/layout/constraints">layout constraints&lt;/a> &lt;em>before&lt;/em> starting.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="learning-takes-time">Learning takes time&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>For the first few weeks I familiarized myself with the various Flutter and Dart concepts, started to narrow in on the app design and make a tiny bit of progress on the app (which I rewrote later in a fraction of the time).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s worthy of note that this project uses almost &lt;em>every&lt;/em> main feature in Flutter. From native platform channels to the somewhat obscure &lt;code>RepaintBoundry&lt;/code> widget, it has it all. This app was packed with a lot of Flutter and Dart things to figure out. Thus, for my first actual Flutter application this wasn&amp;rsquo;t exactly the level a simple to-do app.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That is to say, at that point progress was really slow and it was more of me learning than working on the app.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="my-opinion-of-flutter-and-dart">My opinion of Flutter and Dart&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Fast-forward to today and I&amp;rsquo;ve used Flutter and Dart for ~4 months as of the writing of this post. So far my impression of Flutter and Dart is pretty good.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="flutter">Flutter&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Overall, I&amp;rsquo;ve enjoyed Flutter. Although I&amp;rsquo;ve had multiple headaches with understanding some things (read: layout constraints) initially, I welcomed the well-structured, everything-is-a-widget design and -of course- the hot-reload.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you&amp;rsquo;re looking for a short read to help you decide whether you should use Flutter/Dart for your project, I can confirm much of what &lt;a href="https://medium.com/lightsnap/7-things-we-learned-writing-a-camera-app-in-flutter-ad6a1debe055">this article&lt;/a> states (although its a bit outdated).&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="dart">Dart&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>I felt quite at home with Dart almost straightaway. It has sort of a Javascript/Java/C++ feel to it, but much more well-suited for UI code.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It was actually the quickest I&amp;rsquo;ve ever picked up a programming language. Perhaps because I&amp;rsquo;ve worked with and learned so many programming languages previously or maybe because of its similarities to other languages. Either way, I actually enjoy working with Dart more so than most other languages I know.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="deeply-nested-codeoh-no">Deeply nested code&amp;hellip;oh no&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>One thing that is very apparent when you look at almost any Flutter Dart code is the amount of nesting. This can be obviously &lt;em>very&lt;/em> overwhelming to look at and scroll through. Ideally, you keep the code under control via breaking it out into another widget, etc but oftentimes it can still be a little hairy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thankfully, most modern code editors like VScode have a code folding feature allowing you to collapse function/method bodies, etc and class initializations (in our case for widgets). Until this point I hadn&amp;rsquo;t used this code editor feature, but for Flutter/Dart it is really a time (and eye) saver.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="the-first-milestone">The first milestone&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>After a long and hard month of work, I finally had a barely working version of the capture and some other main features in a rough, unpolished state.&lt;/p>
&lt;figure>&lt;img src="https://noahrahm.com/posts/journey-behind-velocity-lapse-1/rough-version-early-ui.gif"
alt="A gif showing the early working state of Velocity Lapse"/>&lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>The early state of Velocity Lapse. Notice how much the UI has changed since then.&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>It was a nice milestone, because at this point you could capture and render the time lapse to a video (given the proper knowledge, due to its rough and unpolished state).&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="simplify-simplify-simplify">Simplify, simplify, simplify&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Throughout the project, one thing has been constant: the gradual change of the UI towards simplification.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Originally, the UI options were a bit more complicated than they needed to be. I and some select testers tested using the app in real life situations (AKA: we went out and captured time lapses), and it was clear more refinement could be done.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A few things in the capture screen UI weren&amp;rsquo;t 100% clear and I, even though I made the app, mixed up which settings I was changing more than once. (Glare from the sun and sweat on your brow can change the way you use an app). So, I redesigned the tabs to make it more clear which setting was selected and other UI tweaks.&lt;/p>
&lt;figure>&lt;img src="https://noahrahm.com/posts/journey-behind-velocity-lapse-1/capture-screen-ui.jpeg"
alt="The capture screen interface"/>&lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>The capture screen interface&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>Velocity Lapse is meant for everyday people as much as it is for serious time lapse photographers, so I decided to also cut out confusion by using plain English where possible vs. the technical terms.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="logo-design">Logo design&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Over the period of the three months of developing the app, I had sketched about a hundred different logo concepts, both on paper and digitally. Some others tried to sketch some ideas and spent quite a bit of time brainstorming and iterating over potential ideas as well. However, the ideas were either too generic or unrelated, too similar to another logo or just a bad design to begin with.&lt;/p>
&lt;figure>&lt;img src="https://noahrahm.com/posts/journey-behind-velocity-lapse-1/logo-design-sketches.jpg"
alt="Sketches of ideas for the logo"/>&lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Coming up with a logo for Velocity Lapse&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>The name &amp;ldquo;Velocity Lapse&amp;rdquo; did give us some concepts to work with (which we wrote down as tangible objects), but in the end almost none of the ideas were anything we thought would accurately represent the app. The concepts we were coming up with were either too complex or too technical due to &lt;em>velocity&lt;/em> being a bit of a technical, science term.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After praying for an idea or concept to come, it really, literally did. (We cannot underestimate prayer.)&lt;/p>
&lt;figure>&lt;img src="https://noahrahm.com/posts/journey-behind-velocity-lapse-1/logo-design.jpeg"
alt="The Velocity Lapse logo"/>&lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>The Velocity Lapse logo&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>The concept was a camera lens with a spinning-circle shape to show a sense of motion. I did a few variations of it and may end up tweaking/changing it a bit later, but for now it works as a logo.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="setting-up-a-landing-page">Setting up a landing page&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Setting up the landing page for Velocity Lapse was a nice break from developing the app. I purchased the domain name, &lt;em>velocitylapse.com&lt;/em> and setup a landing page where visitors could join a waitlist to get early access to the app.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I didn&amp;rsquo;t actually expect anyone to do so or even find the website since I hadn&amp;rsquo;t promoted it yet, though. It was meant more as a placeholder until the app was ready for a real home page.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With that out of the way, I went back to work on the app.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="development-challenges">Development challenges&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>There was quite a few technical challenges and set-backs in development.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="h264-encoding-artifacts">H.264 encoding artifacts&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>One big set-back in particular had to do with the renderer which would take the captured images and convert them to an H.264 encoded .MP4 video file.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I had been finishing up the &amp;ldquo;last&amp;rdquo; bug fixes and edits before getting the minimal app of the ground and into the internal and open testing stages. However, I discovered that the exported videos had H.264 codec artifacts (banding). The artifacts, ugly bands of pink across the video, seemed to appear after the first second or two of the video. Up until this point I had only rendered out videos less than 2 seconds so I didn&amp;rsquo;t realize this earlier.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This seemed to be an issue with the &lt;a href="https://github.com/jcodec/jcodec">jcodec&lt;/a> Java library that I was using as the encoder for the video export renderer. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t able to produce even one video with jcodec without artifacts. Unfortunately, I hadn&amp;rsquo;t noticed this sooner and so a lot of hours of work implementing the renderer with jcodec had to be thrown away.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Some options were to use:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>The native media APIs for encoding videos&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The NDK with a C++ lib to encode the videos&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>However, after looking at what those require, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t motivated to go in either of those directions writing something from scratch myself.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Obviously, the app couldn&amp;rsquo;t be released without a way to export the timelapse to video, so I needed to think of another way.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After a lot of searching, I came to a small package called &lt;a href="https://github.com/israel-fl/bitmap2video">bitmap2video&lt;/a> which looked like it might do the trick. However, since it was written in Kotlin, it would mean switching the existing code from Java to Kotlin.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I decided to go for it and embrace it as an unexpected opportunity to learn Kotlin.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>First, I did a bunch of extensive testing to verify that it didn&amp;rsquo;t produce artifacts like jcodec. I did end up having to fix some deprecated code and fix a few things to make it work, but came to the conclusion that with some more customization it would indeed work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thankfully, although I&amp;rsquo;ve never written in Kotlin before, the transition was pretty smooth with Android Studio&amp;rsquo;s Java to Kotlin converter, the Kotlin manual, and a bunch of online searches. The most difficult part was wrapping my head around Kotlin&amp;rsquo;s coroutines, but thanks to some articles online I was able to solve the problem I was having.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The end result was a much faster, more lightweight renderer than the one written in Java with jcodec. Plus, since the Kotlin version was a smaller package which I pulled directly into the source, I could benefit from being able to make edits/fixes for Velocity Lapse&amp;rsquo;s specific use case.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So, in the end, it turned out better because of the set-back. :)&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="the-first-pre-release-internal-testing">The first pre-release (internal testing)&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Finally, after 3 months of work the app was in a state that I felt could deserve a pre-release tag. I worked through the process of generating a keystore and generating the app bundle to upload to Google Play for internal testing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the play console, I ended up getting some warnings about sensitive permissions, which I quickly resolved by removing the unnecesary permissions from the Android manifest. Evidently, I had added permissions the app during development while testing some packages and forgot to remove them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After that I was able to successfully release the app bundle to internal testing.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="the-journey-continues">The journey continues&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Thanks for reading. I hope you&amp;rsquo;ve enjoyed this post and have gained something from this journey so far as I have.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you have a suggestion, a comment or some advice, relating either to the app or this post, I&amp;rsquo;d love to hear what you have to share either in the comments below or via &lt;a href="mailto:hi@noahrahm.com">email&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>You can read the next part of the journey in &lt;a href="https://noahrahm.com/posts/journey-behind-velocity-lapse-part-2/">part 2&lt;/a> of this series.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>&lt;em>A big thanks to numerous individuals for their support and advice, making this journey possible. Special thanks to &lt;a href="https://github.com/sundrycode">@sundrycode&lt;/a> for which I am grateful for his help developing the Android native side of the app and taking part in testing. And Yahweh, our Heavenly Father from whom all knowledge and every good thing comes.&lt;/em>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hi, I'm Noah Rahm. An independent designer and developer.</title><link>https://noahrahm.com/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://noahrahm.com/about/</guid><description>&lt;p>Based in the central United States, I provide visual design and development services for organizations, startups, and businesses. I especially love working on meaningful projects that glorify our Heavenly Father, Yahweh, and have a positive impact on others.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’m currently open to new client work and collaboration opportunities, so feel free to get in &lt;a href="mailto:hi@noahrahm.com">get in touch&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="personal">Personal&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>A few of my hobbies include photography, drawing, music, and enjoying Yahweh’s awesome creation with my family.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="other-endeavors">Other endeavors&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve been extremely blessed to work on a lot of different projects with many great people.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Since last year, I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on &lt;a href="https://velocitylapse.com">Velocity Lapse&lt;/a>, an Android app to create time lapses. I&amp;rsquo;m also a part of a project to film high-quality readings of the Psalms in nature called &lt;a href="https://psalms23project.com">The Psalms 23 Project&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Creating things, collaborating with others, and learning new technologies motivate me to create and contribute to open-source projects. Most notably &lt;a href="https://github.com/GimelStudio">Gimel Studio&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://flameshot.org">Flameshot&lt;/a>, and &lt;a href="https://biblenotify.github.io">Bible Notify&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Logo and brand guidelines for a popular C++ library</title><link>https://noahrahm.com/work/openimageio-branding/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://noahrahm.com/work/openimageio-branding/</guid><description>&lt;p>Since OpenImageIO is a library for reading, writing, and processing images, I brainstormed concepts having to do with pixels in an image.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Inspired by &lt;a href="https://openimageio.readthedocs.io/en/latest/_images/grid-small.jpg">this image&lt;/a> from the OpenImageIO docs, I experimented with multiple variations of a pixel grid. The final consensus was a modern, square icon and workmark set in Open Sans bold.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://noahrahm.com/work/openimageio/openimageio-logo-and-branding.webp" alt="OpenImageIO logo" title="OpenImageIO logo">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>The OpenImageIO logo is a trademark of LF Projects, LLC. Used here for my portfolio showcase with permission.&lt;/em>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Logo for a video &amp; photography studio based in the US.</title><link>https://noahrahm.com/work/hilltop-motion-logo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://noahrahm.com/work/hilltop-motion-logo/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://noahrahm.com/work/hilltopmotion/logo-board.webp" alt="Hilltop Motion logo" title="Hilltop Motion logo">&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Modern website for a popular screenshot tool</title><link>https://noahrahm.com/work/flameshot-website/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://noahrahm.com/work/flameshot-website/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>&amp;ldquo;In Flameshot, we were looking for a solution to have a website that can contain various essential aspects into one platform including documentation, FAQ, and also it portrays our software, Flameshot, as a beautiful and easy-to-use&amp;hellip;tool. [Noah] kindly provided our open source project a website based on [the] Zola static website generator, with a beautiful design using modern front-end technologies. At the same time, this reduces the maintenance efforts from our dev team and improves the aesthetics and user-friendliness compared to our previous solution. [He] worked closely with us to tailor the website exactly to our needs. We wholeheartedly recommend [him].&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Mehrad Mahmoudian, on behalf of the Flameshot.org dev team&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://noahrahm.com/work/flameshot/flameshot-website.webp" alt="Flameshot landing page" title="Flameshot landing page light/dark modes">&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Multi-fold business card design for a solar energy consultant</title><link>https://noahrahm.com/work/ozark-solar-business-card-design/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://noahrahm.com/work/ozark-solar-business-card-design/</guid><description>&lt;p>Beau came prepared with a bullet-point list of compelling reasons someone should go with Ozark Solar for their solar energy system installation services.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I worked with him to fine-tune the wording and make sure the most common questions were answered at a glance. It was clear that highlighting that Ozark Solar is a trusted, well-established company with fair benefits was the way to go. Having been in business for over 15 years, Ozark Solar had the experience, knowledge, and honesty that stood out from the competition.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I specifically chose to use images of solar installations that Beau had worked on as a way to showcase his work right on the card. This would provide an opportunity for him to show potential customers real-life examples of his solar installation work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://noahrahm.com/work/ozarksolar/images.jpg" alt="Solar installations" title="Beau's solar installations">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Balancing readability and maintaining a clear, uncluttered design were top priorities. Although it was a multi-fold business card with four areas, it was a unique challenge to include all of the necessary content. In the end, I was able to include more information than what we had originally planned and yet keep a simple layout.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I opted to incorporate elements of Ozark Solar&amp;rsquo;s branding to keep the business card recognizable while allowing the freedom necessary to create something unique and different. The choice of the typeface, Titillium Web, was motivated by the desire to maintain the same look as Ozark Solar&amp;rsquo;s existing logo.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://noahrahm.com/work/ozarksolar/business-card-design-sides.webp" alt="The sides of the business card" title="The four sides of the business card">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Everything came together nicely. Beau was really happy with how the design turned out, and I had an enjoyable time working with him.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>New website for a local, life-impacting organization</title><link>https://noahrahm.com/work/options-of-ava-website/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://noahrahm.com/work/options-of-ava-website/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Options of Ava website has been featured in DesignRush&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href="https://www.designrush.com/best-designs/websites/trends/best-pregnancy-website-designs">best pregnancy website designs&lt;/a> article.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Privacy</title><link>https://noahrahm.com/privacy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://noahrahm.com/privacy/</guid><description>&lt;p>This website does not have analytics or social network buttons that track you. I don’t collect any information about you. Pretty simple, but that means I never know that anyone actually visits my site unless they comment or get it touch&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This site uses third-party web fonts via &lt;a href="https://fonts.coollabs.io/">Coollabs fonts&lt;/a>, a privacy-friendly replacement for Google Fonts. It also uses the &lt;a href="https://unpkg.com">unpkg.com CDN&lt;/a> to serve Alpine.js.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Learn more about the tech this website uses &lt;a href="https://noahrahm.com/colophon/">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Web Design and Development Services</title><link>https://noahrahm.com/services/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://noahrahm.com/services/</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="design-services">Design services&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Website designs that are user-friendly and aesthetically pleasing.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Custom web application designs.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Business cards, flyers, and other promotional materials.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="development-services">Development services&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>I offer development services using modern technologies and best practices. I have years of experience building small to medium-sized web applications from the ground up.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My past work includes a custom e-commerce solution, online directory web applications, and custom Wordpress theme and plugin development.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Custom Laravel web application development&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Custom Wordpress theme and plugin development&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Static website development via Hugo or Sveltekit&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Visual Wordpress &amp;ldquo;development&amp;rdquo; using the Gutenburg block editor&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Website Colophon</title><link>https://noahrahm.com/colophon/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://noahrahm.com/colophon/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Wondering what goes into creating a website like this?&lt;/strong> This page is for you.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="tech">Tech&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Here&amp;rsquo;s the tech stack I used for this site:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://gohugo.io">Hugo&lt;/a> - used to generate the static website.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://tailwindcss.com/">Tailwindcss&lt;/a> - used for the utility-first CSS approach, with my own custom CSS added.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://alpinejs.dev/">Alpine.js&lt;/a> - used for the bits of Javascript functionality on this site.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://fonts.coollabs.io/">Coollabs fonts&lt;/a> - used as a privacy-friendly replacement for Google Fonts.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://pages.github.com/">Github Pages&lt;/a> - used to host this site.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Source code for this website is available in the Github &lt;a href="https://github.com/Correct-Syntax/correct-syntax.github.io">repository&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="visuals">Visuals&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>I designed the pages in &lt;a href="https://icons8.com/lunacy">Lunacy&lt;/a> (I don&amp;rsquo;t really care for the name) and created whatever other mockups and graphics were necessary myself using a combination of &lt;a href="https://blender.org">Blender&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://gimp.org">GIMP&lt;/a>, and &lt;a href="https://affinity.serif.com/en-us/designer/">Affinity Designer&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>