<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>design on Noah Rahm</title><link>https://noahrahm.com/tags/design/</link><description>Recent content in design on Noah Rahm</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://noahrahm.com/tags/design/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Timeline of a Typical Creative Project</title><link>https://noahrahm.com/posts/timeline-of-creative-project/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://noahrahm.com/posts/timeline-of-creative-project/</guid><description>&lt;p>The title read, &amp;ldquo;The Timeline of a Typical Project&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I stopped to read it and thought it was the best illustration of the creative process I&amp;rsquo;ve ever seen. Thus, it could just as appropriately have been entitled &amp;ldquo;Timeline of a Typical Creative Project&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I created my own version of the timeline to remind myself of an important fact about working on any project (especially a creative one).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In almost any creative process, there is a point early on where what you&amp;rsquo;ve done just looks plain &lt;em>ugly&lt;/em>. It&amp;rsquo;s the ugly stage when the voice in your head says to throw it out and restart.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, if you can push through the early, ugly stage and continue the process, you&amp;rsquo;ll often find ways to refine your work later in the process to be better. Often, you&amp;rsquo;ll find that it&amp;rsquo;s not as bad as you first thought.&lt;/p>
&lt;figure>&lt;img src="https://noahrahm.com/posts/timeline-creative-project/timeline.webp"
alt="Timeline of a typical creative project"/>&lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Timeline of a typical creative project&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>The typical creative project goes something like this:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At the beginning, we&amp;rsquo;re excited to get our ideas out of our head. We start to put ideas to pixels (or paper, or whatever) and discover that this is going to be harder to accomplish than what we originally thought.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It quickly moves from &amp;ldquo;hmmm, this is going to be a lot of work&amp;rdquo;, to doubting what we&amp;rsquo;ve already done and possibly getting bored with the process thus far.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Finally, frustration can creep in, and we feel like giving up. Either restarting again or totally throwing out the idea altogether.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then we think to ourselves, &amp;ldquo;On second thought, it would be good to finish this because I&amp;rsquo;ll learn something for next time.&amp;rdquo; So, we continue and make the best of our work, finding ways to improve it or hide any blemishes from earlier in the process.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the end, we look at our completed work and realize it&amp;rsquo;s not that bad after all.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One time I was working on a live design session in person with a client.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Seeing the ideas I was coming up with early in the process, the client seemed a bit concerned that they weren&amp;rsquo;t going to match the brief. I reassured them that making &amp;ldquo;ideations&amp;rdquo; to explore design concepts was a necessary part of the process.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As the process progressed and the designs became refined, they understood that an &amp;ldquo;ugly&amp;rdquo; stage was necessary to get to the final design. In the end, they loved the design and were appreciative of my work because they saw the process to get to the final result.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You need to realize that it is just part of the creative process to have lows, especially in the early stages, where everything inside screams to restart because your work isn&amp;rsquo;t matching your expectations.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is what people mean when they say to &amp;ldquo;trust the process&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At the really low part of a project, you can feel as though if you just &amp;ldquo;restart clean, anew&amp;rdquo;, everything will be better. However, I haven&amp;rsquo;t found that to be the case the majority of the time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Until you develop the experience to know when it&amp;rsquo;s actually best to restart, its good to &amp;ldquo;trust the process&amp;rdquo;, get your work past those early stages, and see where that leads you.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Even if the creative idea doesn&amp;rsquo;t end up being great, at least you&amp;rsquo;ve allowed it to go through the process, and you&amp;rsquo;ve completed something.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mindlessly going in a loop of restarting during the ugly stage is not fun and is one of the fastest ways to get frustrated and get nowhere at the same time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The picture of an artist or writer repeatedly restarting their work only to crinkle the paper and toss it into the overflowing trash bin is not something to aspire to for your work. While it does illustrate the reality of sorting through many ideas to find the good one, don&amp;rsquo;t expect that mindlessly restarting every time your work doesn&amp;rsquo;t meet your expectations is going to yield something useful.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There is a balance. You could fill pages in a sketchbook with sketches of logo ideas and do so quickly to not get too attached to an idea. However, it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be a good idea to quit on a potentially good design concept before you&amp;rsquo;ve explored the possibilities.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At least for me, once I try to transfer what looks so good in my head down to pixels on the screen or lines on paper, I have to resist the urge to nitpick it too early in the process.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The key is ultimately to be patient and not stress out, especially early in the process.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Remembering the timeline of a typical project might help&amp;hellip;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>20+ Free Resources for Digital Design</title><link>https://noahrahm.com/posts/free-resources-for-digital-design/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://noahrahm.com/posts/free-resources-for-digital-design/</guid><description>&lt;p>As a visual designer, having a good set of resources within arm&amp;rsquo;s reach is not only helpful but necessary.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>While there are a ton of really great paid design services and resources that can make life a lot easier, the focus of this list is on &lt;strong>the best free resources&lt;/strong> that I&amp;rsquo;ve personally collected over time. Many of these I&amp;rsquo;ve been using for years for my own &lt;a href="https://noahrahm.com/work/">design work&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Whether you&amp;rsquo;re a web, app, UI, UX designer, or none of the above, there&amp;rsquo;s likely at least a few things here you could consider adding to your toolkit.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Special thanks to all the individuals and companies that made these resources available for designers like us to use free of charge!&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="typography">Typography&lt;/h3>
&lt;figure>&lt;img src="https://noahrahm.com/posts/free-resources-for-digital-design/fontjoy.jpg"
alt="A screenshot of FontJoy"/>&lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>FontJoy in action. Yes, sometimes it comes up with wild combinations&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://fontjoy.com/">FontJoy&lt;/a> is a really nice font pairing web application tool that generates font combinations with deep learning. If you know what style you&amp;rsquo;re after (and have some patience), it can come up with some nice font pairs for you to consider.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://typespiration.com/">Typespiration&lt;/a> If you&amp;rsquo;re needing some inspiration for type, you can take a look at Typespiration for some designs and guides for font combinations.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://fontba.se/">FontBase&lt;/a> A cross-platform font manager. A very useful tool for using Google/Adobe fonts in any application.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://typescale.com/">Type Scale&lt;/a> is a visual calculator you can use to size your typography.&lt;/p>
&lt;figure>&lt;img src="https://noahrahm.com/posts/free-resources-for-digital-design/typescale.jpg"
alt="A screenshot of Typescale"/>&lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Typescale&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.fontsinthewild.com/">Fontsinthewild.com&lt;/a> Sometimes you just have to see a font used in order to get inspiration to use it in your design. That is the basic premise of fontsinthewild.com, where you browse screenshots of different fonts used on sites &amp;ldquo;in the wild&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://v-fonts.com/">v-fonts&lt;/a> Experiment with variable fonts.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://fontspark.netlify.app/">FontSpark&lt;/a> is a simple tool to find different fonts.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.pairandcompare.net/">Pair and Compare&lt;/a> is a great way to mix and match different Google fonts to find the best combination for your design.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Want a good reading resource to improve your typography skills? Read &lt;a href="https://practicaltypography.com/">Butterick&amp;rsquo;s Practical Typography&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="color-resources">Color resources&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://palx.jxnblk.com/">palx.jxnblk.com&lt;/a> is a very helpful tool for generating a full-spectrum color palette from a single color. I mainly use it when I need to quickly generate a range of grays for a UI design.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://toolness.github.io/accessible-color-matrix/">Accessible color matrix&lt;/a> Accessibility is an important part of choosing colors for a website or app design. This accessible color matrix tool allows you to check if your color combinations conform to accessibility standards.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://hihayk.github.io/scale">ihayk.github.io/scale&lt;/a> A creative way to experiment with different color ranges.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="icon-sets">Icon sets&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://simpleicons.org/">Simple Icons&lt;/a> Very useful and vast collection of 2750 SVG icons for popular brands. I haven&amp;rsquo;t found any brands I&amp;rsquo;ve ever needed to &lt;em>not&lt;/em> be in the Simple Icons collection.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://phosphoricons.com/">Phosphoricons&lt;/a> Open-source icon family offering 6 weights: thin, light, regular, bold, fill, and duotone. Needless to say, it is a very useful and large (1,248+) collection worth bookmarking.&lt;/p>
&lt;figure>&lt;img src="https://noahrahm.com/posts/free-resources-for-digital-design/phosphor-icons.jpg"
alt="A screenshot of the Phosphor icons website"/>&lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Phosphor icon family. Go bookmark it —it&amp;rsquo;s worth the bookmark.&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;h3 id="software">Software&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://icons8.com/lunacy">Lunacy&lt;/a> (A.K.A. Sketch for Windows). Although I don’t care for the name, it’s my primary design tool. Being a native Windows application makes it fast and smooth to work with. Lunacy works &lt;em>completely offline&lt;/em> and has almost everything I&amp;rsquo;ve ever needed for creating web and graphic designs, having worked with it for the past 3 years.&lt;/p>
&lt;figure>&lt;img src="https://noahrahm.com/posts/free-resources-for-digital-design/lunacy.jpg"
alt="A screenshot of Lunacy open with a logo design document"/>&lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Lunacy—my (current) go-to design tool open to my logo design for Hilltop Motion.&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://penpot.app">PenPot&lt;/a> is an open-source, web-based design and prototyping tool based on open standards.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="templates">Templates&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>If you need something for a specific design software, there are sites that provide free UI kits, icons, templates, mockups, style guides, illustrations, and more. My experience is that you do have to look through a lot of &amp;ldquo;okay&amp;rdquo; stuff to find the gold, though.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="sketch">Sketch&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://sketchelements.com/">SketchElements&lt;/a> is a place to find free Sketch resources. The files can be used with either Lunacy or Sketch.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="figma">Figma&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Similar to SketchElements.com above, &lt;a href="https://figmaelements.com/">FigmaElements&lt;/a> offers free Figma resources.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="mockups">Mockups&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.ls.graphics/free-mockups">ls.graphics&lt;/a> Free, high-quality mockups from ls.graphics.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://mockuphone.com/">MockUPhone&lt;/a> is by far the best free resource I have discovered for generating device mockups. The site allows you to wrap your design in a variety of mobile device frames, including iPhones, iPads, Android phones, laptops, and wearables. The mockups are licensed under the Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 Unported License, making them usable for practically any project.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Another resource for generating Android mockups is the official &lt;a href="https://developer.android.com/distribute/marketing-tools/device-art-generator">Android Device Art Generator&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="assets">Assets&lt;/h3>
&lt;figure>&lt;img src="https://noahrahm.com/posts/free-resources-for-digital-design/haikei.jpg"
alt="A screenshot of Haikei generating a layered peaks svg background"/>&lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>You can generate all sorts of backgrounds with Haikei.&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>Both &lt;a href="https://superdesigner.co/">superdesigner.co&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://haikei.app/">haikei.app&lt;/a> let you generate SVG assets like backgrounds, blobs, patterns, gradients, and shapes for your designs.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="conclusion">Conclusion&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Thanks for reading. I hope you enjoyed this list of design resources and tools.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>This aims to be a growing list of the best free resources for design, so check back for updates. Last updated 11/21/2023&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Do you have any free design tools or resources you use that I didn&amp;rsquo;t mention? Feel free to comment below.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>