<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Musings on Noah Rahm</title><link>https://noahrahm.com/tags/musings/</link><description>Recent content in Musings on Noah Rahm</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://noahrahm.com/tags/musings/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The "Law" of No-s and Yes-es</title><link>https://noahrahm.com/posts/law-of-nos-and-yeses/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://noahrahm.com/posts/law-of-nos-and-yeses/</guid><description>&lt;p>If you say &lt;em>Yes&lt;/em> to something now, it usually means saying &lt;em>No&lt;/em> to something later. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter whether it is making a purchase or adding a new task to your schedule.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ultimately, what you say &amp;ldquo;Yes&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;No&amp;rdquo; to determines the course of your life. It&amp;rsquo;s called making a decision.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Although some people may try to avoid it via debt or overworking, it is consistent: Unlike Yahweh our Heavenly Father, we are finite in our time and resources. Thus, we must make decisions. We must eventually say &amp;ldquo;No&amp;rdquo; to something and close the door in our lives, as hard as that can be sometimes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In reality, we are constantly making decisions all the time. Unless we did, we would not be able to accomplish much.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What we decide usually comes down to what is most important to us; that is, what we &lt;em>value&lt;/em> most.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It is said that your life is made up of a series of decisions. Another way of saying it might be that your life is made up of what you said &lt;em>Yes&lt;/em> or &lt;em>No&lt;/em> to.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It seems to me that Yahweh caused it to be like this to test us.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Will we put Him first in our lives? Will we spend our time building His Kingdom, or just our own?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We are all given many decisions to make? How will we choose? What will we say &lt;em>Yes&lt;/em> to? What will we say &lt;em>No&lt;/em> to?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Food for thought on slang</title><link>https://noahrahm.com/posts/food-for-thought-on-slang/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://noahrahm.com/posts/food-for-thought-on-slang/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="what-does-it-mean">&amp;ldquo;What does it mean?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>One word in particular I&amp;rsquo;ve always wondered about is &amp;ldquo;sucks,&amp;rdquo; specifically when used in the phrase, &amp;ldquo;that sucks.&amp;rdquo; I&amp;rsquo;ve never understood what it actually meant when people would say, &amp;ldquo;That sucks.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Whenever I heard it, I made a mental note to look it up, but I hadn&amp;rsquo;t actually remembered to do so until recently.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="looking-it-up">Looking it up&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>According to the &lt;a href="https://usdictionary.com/idioms/that-sucks/">US Dictionary&lt;/a>:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The phrase &amp;ldquo;that sucks&amp;rdquo; has its roots in American English slang from the 20th century. It&amp;rsquo;s an offshoot of older slang where &amp;ldquo;suck&amp;rdquo; was used as a term of derision or insult. Later on, it evolved into a more general expression of dissatisfaction or empathy for an unfortunate situation.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Some dictionaries say it&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em>&amp;ldquo;rude slang,&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em> while others (like this one) take a slightly different stance. Indeed, it&amp;rsquo;s at least &lt;em>derived&lt;/em> from a slang term.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It appears that there&amp;rsquo;s not a clear consensus on whether or not the phrase is considered rude, but it&amp;rsquo;s definitely not considered appropriate in professional or non-casual settings.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Based on the origin, the phrase does seem more rude and insulting than empathetic.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="a-broader-question">A broader question&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>After looking into that, I had a broader question.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Would it be correct to put slang into the same category as swearing and profanity?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To answer that, I first needed to understand what slang is.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With some research, I found that because slang varies from culture to culture and changes from generation to generation, it can be hard to pin down &lt;em>exactly&lt;/em> how to define it. Some people generally define slang as &lt;em>any&lt;/em> informal speech, while others have a tighter definition (sounds familiar, right?).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The American Heritage® Dictionary of the English Language, 5th Edition, defines slang as:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;em>noun&lt;/em> A kind of language occurring chiefly in casual and playful speech, made up typically of coinages and figures of speech that are deliberately used in place of standard terms for added raciness, humor, irreverence, or other effect.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h3 id="slang-as-euphemisms-for-cursing">Slang as euphemisms for cursing&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Most believers (if they knew) would probably agree that if the slang term is simply an euphemism for cursing or using our Heavenly Father&amp;rsquo;s name in an inappropriate way, then it would be wrong to use it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>An euphemism is using a word that doesn&amp;rsquo;t sound as bad as the original word, but the meaning is the same. I won&amp;rsquo;t give examples here, but suffice to say that there is no real difference between using a curse word and an euphemism for it since the intent is basically the same.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Keeping that in mind, what about other slang?&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="other-slang">Other slang&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s wise to think about our wording because our words are important. &lt;em>&amp;ldquo;Death and life are in the power of the tongue. (Proverbs 18:21a)&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Do we build people up and tear people down through the words we use?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Biblical standard is that we let no corrupt word proceed out of our mouth, &lt;em>&amp;ldquo;but what is good for necessary edification, that it may impart grace to the hearers.&amp;rdquo; (Ephesians 4:29)&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In essence, we should say what is going to build someone up and show love to them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The answer to my question largly depends on the definition you use to define &amp;ldquo;slang,&amp;rdquo; as well as what you consider &amp;ldquo;edifying&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m not sure whether slang (that is not a euphemism for cursing) can 100% be put into the same category as swearing and profanity.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, personally, I think it becomes a little clearer if we consider that the purpose for &lt;em>any&lt;/em> speech should be edification.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If the goal of our speech is edification, then any type of speech that isn&amp;rsquo;t edifying probably isn&amp;rsquo;t something appropriate for a believer to include in their speech. I&amp;rsquo;m not convinced that the above definition of slang indicates that it would be.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have come across various articles bringing up some good points about benefits of knowing slang. While I agree that it can be useful for culture and understanding those that do use it, that might be the extent of it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed that using slang communicates a less serious composure and one that might not always be fitting for a believer.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I think about the fact that, as believers, we are to be representatives of Yahushua, our Savior, to the world.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If we are deliberately adding &lt;em>&amp;ldquo;racy, irreverent, or rude&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em> words to our speech, are we necessarily being a good witness?&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>