<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Writing on Noah Rahm</title><link>https://noahrahm.com/tags/writing/</link><description>Recent content in Writing on Noah Rahm</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://noahrahm.com/tags/writing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>On writing</title><link>https://noahrahm.com/posts/on-writing/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://noahrahm.com/posts/on-writing/</guid><description>&lt;p>Something everyone writing and posting online knows:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Writing and sharing publicly online is intimidating and a little awkward, especially at first.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve been posting for almost a couple years now, but I still hesitate every time I start to write.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, even the handful of posts I&amp;rsquo;ve written thus far have been helpful in my personal development and in improving my writing (one of my goals for writing posts in the first place).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I thought I would write on why I write posts and my struggles with it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let&amp;rsquo;s see how this goes.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="my-experiences">My experiences&lt;/h3>
&lt;h4 id="hesitations">Hesitations&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>For a long time I had hesitations that kept me from beginning to write and share it publicly. I felt like I didn&amp;rsquo;t know anything (and I still don&amp;rsquo;t) worth sharing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, the reality is that everyone has &lt;em>something&lt;/em> that Yahweh has given to them to share. If writing posts online is the means of sharing that, then we just need to be a willing vessel that Yahweh can use.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We ought to also realize that writing about something doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean you know &lt;em>everything&lt;/em> about the topic, and it certainly doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean that you know &lt;em>every-thing&lt;/em> (despite what some may think).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I also don&amp;rsquo;t believe you have to come across as anything but sharing your thoughts and experiences. It&amp;rsquo;s okay to say you&amp;rsquo;re still learning and an open to correction. &lt;em>It&amp;rsquo;s okay to say you don&amp;rsquo;t know.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="first-steps">First steps&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>I published my first post on a different website almost 4 years ago. It is no longer available online now, but it was an important step for me. Between then and the time when I started writing and posting on this website was 2 years.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Since then I have posted quite infrequently, but now I look back on what I wrote and see the progress.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I sometimes cringe, but I realize that its part of learning.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="struggles">Struggles&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m still working on how to articulate things in such a way that doesn&amp;rsquo;t use &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rdquo; every sentence.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Something I really like about my website is I don&amp;rsquo;t have to feel the pressure to say or do anything particular. Thankfully, (at least right now) I have the liberty to speak my mind. Also, since it&amp;rsquo;s my own website, there isn&amp;rsquo;t an algorithm deciding which posts you see.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sometimes, though, I forget that and crawl back into &amp;ldquo;a shell&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="why-i-write">Why I write&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>It helps to know the &lt;em>why&lt;/em> whenever you&amp;rsquo;re doing something.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here&amp;rsquo;s mine:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>1.&lt;/strong> I write posts because I want to share things that have helped me or just to relate something I find interesting which might interest others.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>2.&lt;/strong> I&amp;rsquo;d like to improve my writing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the second point, its true that there is more to getting better at writing than just the act of writing, but sitting down and writing is still the first step.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For each post, I try to be intentional and focus on improving something about my writing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This time I&amp;rsquo;m trying to be more loose and add more variety. Feel free to let me know if I suceeded.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="deciding-what-to-write">Deciding what to write&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Many people wonder, &amp;ldquo;Well, what should I write?&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I had the same question until I realized that it goes back to your &lt;em>why&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Me telling you what to write would be pointless because it assumes that either A) you have the same motives and experiences as I do, or B) I&amp;rsquo;m your teacher giving you an assignment. :)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What I&amp;rsquo;ve found is that for me, the things that I can most easily write about are the ideas that have moved or deeply affected me in some way. Those that made me &lt;strong>feel&lt;/strong> something. Sometimes it is what someone said, or what Yahweh showed me, or questions and thoughts I&amp;rsquo;ve thought about which spark the idea for a post.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I personally dislike the idea of creating &amp;ldquo;content&amp;rdquo; just-for-the-sake-of-it. The internet and life in general already have enough distractions that we don&amp;rsquo;t need more fluff.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The saying, &amp;ldquo;the pen is mightier than the sword&amp;rdquo; is good, but one that is even better is &amp;ldquo;The wise man knows when to pick the pen up&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>