<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Portfolio of Selected Work on Noah Rahm</title><link>https://noahrahm.com/work/</link><description>Recent content in Portfolio of Selected Work on Noah Rahm</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://noahrahm.com/work/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Logo and brand guidelines for a popular C++ library</title><link>https://noahrahm.com/work/openimageio-branding/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://noahrahm.com/work/openimageio-branding/</guid><description>&lt;p>Since OpenImageIO is a library for reading, writing, and processing images I brainstormed concepts having to do with pixels of an image.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Inspired by &lt;a href="https://openimageio.readthedocs.io/en/latest/_images/grid-small.jpg">this image&lt;/a> from the OpenImageIO docs, I experimented with multiple variations of a pixel grid. The final consensus was a modern, square icon and workmark set in Open Sans bold.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://noahrahm.com/work/openimageio/openimageio-logo-and-branding.webp" alt="OpenImageIO logo" title="OpenImageIO logo">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>The OpenImageIO logo is a trademark of LF Projects, LLC. Used here for my portfolio showcase with permission.&lt;/em>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Logo for a video &amp; photography studio based in the US.</title><link>https://noahrahm.com/work/hilltop-motion-logo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://noahrahm.com/work/hilltop-motion-logo/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://noahrahm.com/work/hilltopmotion/logo-board.webp" alt="Hilltop Motion logo" title="Hilltop Motion logo">&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Modern website for a popular screenshot tool</title><link>https://noahrahm.com/work/flameshot-website/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://noahrahm.com/work/flameshot-website/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Multi-fold business card design for a solar energy consultant</title><link>https://noahrahm.com/work/ozark-solar-business-card-design/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://noahrahm.com/work/ozark-solar-business-card-design/</guid><description>&lt;p>Beau came prepared with a bullet-point list of compelling reasons someone should to go with Ozark Solar for their solar energy system installation services.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I worked with him to fine-tune the wording and make sure the most common questions were answered at a glance. It was clear that highlighting that Ozark Solar is a trusted, well-established company with fair benefits was the way to go. Having been in business for over 15 years, Ozark Solar had the experience, knowledge, and honesty that stood out from the competition.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I specifically chose to use images of solar installations that Beau had worked on as a way to showcase his work right on the card. This would provide an opportunity for him to show potential customers real-life examples of his solar installation work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://noahrahm.com/work/ozarksolar/images.jpg" alt="Solar installations" title="Beau's solar installations">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Balancing readability and a maintaining a clear, uncluttered design was a top priority. Although it was a multi-fold business card with four areas, it was a unique challenge to include all of the necessary content. In the end, I was able to include more information than what we had originally planned and yet keep a simple layout.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I opted to incorporate elements of Ozark Solar&amp;rsquo;s branding to keep the business card recognizable, while allowing the freedom necessary to create something unique and different. The choice of the typeface, Titillium Web, was motivated out of maintaining the same look of Ozark Solar&amp;rsquo;s existing logo.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://noahrahm.com/work/ozarksolar/business-card-design-sides.webp" alt="The sides of the business card" title="The four sides of the business card">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Everything came together nicely. Beau was really happy with how the design turned out and I had an enjoyable time working with him.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>New website for a local, life-impacting organization</title><link>https://noahrahm.com/work/options-of-ava-website/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://noahrahm.com/work/options-of-ava-website/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Options of Ava website has been featured in DesignRush&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href="https://www.designrush.com/best-designs/websites/trends/best-pregnancy-website-designs">best pregnancy website designs&lt;/a> article.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>