<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Portfolio of Selected Work on Noah Rahm</title><link>https://noahrahm.com/work/</link><description>Recent content in Portfolio of Selected Work on Noah Rahm</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://noahrahm.com/work/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Android app for creating time-lapse videos</title><link>https://noahrahm.com/work/velocity-lapse/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://noahrahm.com/work/velocity-lapse/</guid><description>&lt;p>I typically work on web design and development projects, so Velocity Lapse is a way for me to lean into mobile app design and development, app marketing, and user support. Creating Velocity Lapse combines my passion for photography with my design and development skills for the unique challenges in creating a mobile app.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve already written a few thousand words about the process in a &lt;a href="https://noahrahm.com/posts/journey-behind-velocity-lapse-part-1/">series of posts&lt;/a> if you&amp;rsquo;d like to get a glimpse of my journey in creating the app.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Logo and brand guidelines for a popular C++ library</title><link>https://noahrahm.com/work/openimageio-branding/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://noahrahm.com/work/openimageio-branding/</guid><description>&lt;p>When working on a logo design project, I begin with a research phase to learn about the industry and client. Looking through existing OpenImageIO materials, I found &lt;a href="https://openimageio.readthedocs.io/en/latest/_images/grid-small.jpg">an image of a pixel grid&lt;/a> in the OpenImageIO documentation. It gave me the idea to experiment with variations of a simplified pixel grid.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Since OpenImageIO is a library for reading, writing, and processing images, I brainstormed concepts having to do with pixels in an image, image processing, and file I/O.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With feedback from Larry Gritz, OpenImageIO&amp;rsquo;s maintainer, and others, I refined the concept to a square with a grid of pixels and a gradient, representing the processing of an image. The final consensus was the logo concept with a square icon and a wordmark set in Open Sans bold.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://noahrahm.com/work/openimageio/openimageio-logo-and-branding.webp" alt="OpenImageIO logo" title="OpenImageIO logo">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Once the logo concept was finalized, I created different color variations of the logo for potential use cases, and included guidelines for use in a brand guidelines book. I also created a few promotional graphics.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The OpenImageIO logo was a success, helping OpenImageIO meet the logo requirement for inclusion in the Academy Software Foundation&amp;rsquo;s projects, and providing a proper representation of the 15-year-old project.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>The OpenImageIO logo is a trademark of LF Projects, LLC. Used with permission.&lt;/em>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Logo for a video &amp; photography studio based in the US.</title><link>https://noahrahm.com/work/hilltop-motion-logo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://noahrahm.com/work/hilltop-motion-logo/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://noahrahm.com/work/hilltopmotion/logo-board.webp" alt="Hilltop Motion logo" title="Hilltop Motion logo">&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Modern website for a popular screenshot tool</title><link>https://noahrahm.com/work/flameshot-website/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://noahrahm.com/work/flameshot-website/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>&amp;quot;[For] Flameshot, we were looking for a solution to have a website that can contain various essential aspects into one platform including documentation, FAQ, and also it portrays our software, Flameshot, as a beautiful and easy-to-use&amp;hellip;tool. [Noah] kindly provided our open source project a website based on [the] Zola static website generator, with a beautiful design using modern front-end technologies. At the same time, this reduces the maintenance efforts from our dev team and improves the aesthetics and user-friendliness compared to our previous solution. [He] worked closely with us to tailor the website exactly to our needs. We wholeheartedly recommend [him].&amp;quot;&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Mehrad Mahmoudian, on behalf of the Flameshot.org dev team&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://noahrahm.com/work/flameshot/flameshot-website.webp" alt="Flameshot landing page" title="Flameshot landing page light/dark modes">&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Multi-fold business card design for a solar energy consultant</title><link>https://noahrahm.com/work/ozark-solar-business-card-design/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://noahrahm.com/work/ozark-solar-business-card-design/</guid><description>&lt;p>Beau came prepared with a bullet-point list of compelling reasons someone should go with Ozark Solar for their solar energy system installation services.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I worked with him to fine-tune the wording and make sure the most common questions were answered at a glance. It was clear that highlighting that Ozark Solar is a trusted, well-established company with fair benefits was the way to go. Having been in business for over 15 years, Ozark Solar had the experience, knowledge, and honesty that stood out from the competition.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I specifically chose to use images of solar installations that Beau had worked on as a way to showcase his work right on the card. This would provide an opportunity for him to show potential customers real-life examples of his solar installation work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://noahrahm.com/work/ozarksolar/images.jpg" alt="Solar installations" title="Beau's solar installations">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Balancing readability and maintaining a clear, uncluttered design were top priorities. Although it was a multi-fold business card with four areas, it was a unique challenge to include all of the necessary content. In the end, I was able to include more information than what we had originally planned and yet keep a simple layout.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I opted to incorporate elements of Ozark Solar&amp;rsquo;s branding to keep the business card recognizable while allowing the freedom necessary to create something unique and different. The choice of the typeface, Titillium Web, was motivated by the desire to maintain the same look as Ozark Solar&amp;rsquo;s existing logo.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://noahrahm.com/work/ozarksolar/business-card-design-sides.webp" alt="The sides of the business card" title="The four sides of the business card">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Everything came together nicely. Beau was really happy with how the design turned out, and I had an enjoyable time working with him.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>New website for a local, life-impacting organization</title><link>https://noahrahm.com/work/options-of-ava-website/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://noahrahm.com/work/options-of-ava-website/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Options of Ava website has been featured in DesignRush&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href="https://www.designrush.com/best-designs/websites/trends/best-pregnancy-website-designs">best pregnancy website designs&lt;/a> article.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Open-source, flexible content management system for static websites.</title><link>https://noahrahm.com/work/steadycms/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://noahrahm.com/work/steadycms/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Open-source, node based 2D graphics editor with a Python API</title><link>https://noahrahm.com/work/gimel-studio/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://noahrahm.com/work/gimel-studio/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>