<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Essays on Noah Rahm</title><link>https://noahrahm.com/tags/essays/</link><description>Recent content in Essays on Noah Rahm</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://noahrahm.com/tags/essays/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Life Lessons from 2022</title><link>https://noahrahm.com/posts/life-lessons-2022/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://noahrahm.com/posts/life-lessons-2022/</guid><description>&lt;p>In the past year I&amp;rsquo;ve made a greater effort to look for what Yahweh, our Heavenly Father, is try to show me in every situation. There is always something to learn, even in the darkest of situations. :)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Life is a journey. A believer&amp;rsquo;s life is continuing to grow in Yahushua (commonly called &amp;ldquo;Jesus&amp;rdquo;). It is following the footsteps of the Savior. Learning little, by little.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ll say that it is much easier to learn the lessons He is trying to teach you the first time. Though, if you don&amp;rsquo;t stop to think about what He is showing you, then you probably won&amp;rsquo;t learn it.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="lessons">Lessons&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>So, here is my reflection of life lessons that stand out the most from what I&amp;rsquo;ve learned this past year. I&amp;rsquo;ve intentionally left these rather general so that you can see how these can apply in difference circumstances.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="precedence">Precedence&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Things need to be Yahweh&amp;rsquo;s way from the very start, to begin with. The first meeting of something is probably how the rest will be. First impression &lt;em>is&lt;/em> important. Subsequent meetings will probably follow the same pattern and it is hard to steer it right again.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="confrontation">Confrontation&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>As hard as it is, if you can&amp;rsquo;t overlook something in another believer, you must confront the person and make it right. Follow Matthew 18.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>15&lt;/strong> &amp;ldquo;Moreover if your brother sins against you, go and tell him his fault between you and him alone. If he hears you, you have gained your brother. &lt;strong>16&lt;/strong> But if he will not hear, take with you one or two more, that &amp;lsquo;by the mouth of two or three witnesses every word may be established.&amp;rsquo; &lt;strong>17&lt;/strong> And if he refuses to hear them, tell it to the church. But if he refuses even to hear the church, let him be to you like a heathen and a tax collector.&amp;rdquo; -Matt. 18:15-17&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Don&amp;rsquo;t wait to resolve an issue with someone if it cannot be forgotten. The longer it goes on, the harder it will be to resolve. Glossing over problems and avoiding talking about them &lt;strong>doesn&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/strong> solve the problem.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="expectations">Expectations&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Misunderstandings and conflicts can happen when both parties are not clear on their expectations. Be clear what you expect from others and clarify their expectations of you.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="loyalty">Loyalty&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Remember who you are working for and who your loyalty belongs to. People &lt;strong>will&lt;/strong> fail. People &lt;strong>will&lt;/strong> have conflicts.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Remember that you are not working for men but for Yahweh. Don&amp;rsquo;t be discouraged. Be loyal to Yahweh and the calling &lt;strong>He&lt;/strong> has called you to.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Whatever you do, do your work heartily, as for Yahweh rather than for men&amp;rdquo; -Colossians 3:23&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h4 id="communication">Communication&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Remember that life is about relationships and without communication, there is no relationship.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Never be too busy to listen to others or talk to them, especially if you have a conflict. Remember that it is a two-way street. Both parties need to talk &lt;strong>and&lt;/strong> listen to the other.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Remember that the most important communication is with Yahweh through prayer.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="patience">Patience&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Wait&lt;/strong> for Yahweh&amp;rsquo;s timing and plan. Don&amp;rsquo;t rush ahead without His leading.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Trust in Yahweh with all your heart, And lean not on your own understanding; In all your ways acknowledge Him, And He shall direct your paths.&amp;rdquo; -Proverbs 3:5-6&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>However, don&amp;rsquo;t confuse patience with procrastination(!) or lack of faith.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="judgement">Judgement&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Make sure you hear both sides and have the facts before you judge a matter. Don&amp;rsquo;t be too quick to blame or release from blame.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As hard as it is, wait until you have &lt;strong>all&lt;/strong> of the information about the situation before making a judgement. Don&amp;rsquo;t feel pressured to make a judgement hastily.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="facts">Facts&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Don&amp;rsquo;t assume you have all the facts or think you know something about someone or something. It is easy to be &amp;ldquo;in the moment&amp;rdquo; and end up making up things, assuming things that aren&amp;rsquo;t true.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="self-imposed-rules">Self-Imposed Rules&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Don&amp;rsquo;t seek to establish your &lt;strong>own&lt;/strong> form of righteousness. Study the Scriptures and walk out Yahweh&amp;rsquo;s righteousness. Don&amp;rsquo;t look down on those that do not follow your self-imposed rules, even if they are good, but not necessarily from Scripture.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="appearance">Appearance&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Remember that sometimes people will assume things about you based on &lt;strong>appearance&lt;/strong> or by what you &lt;strong>don&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/strong> say as much as what you do say. Don&amp;rsquo;t take it personally if someone thinks bad of you because of it. Yahweh justifies.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="compromise">Compromise&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Compromising on what Scripture says, even a little bit, opens the door to a continuous erosion of it from your life. Once the door is open, it is hard to close. Be sure that any compromise you make &lt;strong>does not compromise your belief in Yahweh&amp;rsquo;s Word.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="jealousy">Jealousy&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Don&amp;rsquo;t get jealous of other people&amp;rsquo;s situations, etc. Jealousy stems from discontentment. The grass &lt;strong>isn&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/strong> greener on the other side of the fence. &lt;strong>Everyone&lt;/strong> has their own set of problems and they may be worse than yours. Be content where Yahweh has placed you in life.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="be-humble-be-real">Be Humble; Be Real&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Be humble, knowing that you deserve death, but Yahweh showed you mercy and grace. Show the same mercy and grace that He shows to &lt;strong>You&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Do not look down on others for what you &lt;strong>think&lt;/strong> they do not know or practice. You also have things that Yahweh is trying to get your attention about and you must be humble to even see what He is trying to teach you.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Everyone&lt;/strong> has problems and struggles they deal with. Don&amp;rsquo;t act like you have everything together when it is not the case. Even people, in general, will appreciate your honesty in admitting that you have struggles over acting like you have it all together.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="conclusion">Conclusion&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>I hope this post has blessed and encouraged you. If you would like to share life lessons &lt;strong>you&lt;/strong> have learned this past year, I would love to hear what they are in the comments below.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>