<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Faith on Noah Rahm</title><link>https://noahrahm.com/tags/faith/</link><description>Recent content in Faith on Noah Rahm</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://noahrahm.com/tags/faith/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Food for thought on slang</title><link>https://noahrahm.com/posts/food-for-thought-on-slang/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://noahrahm.com/posts/food-for-thought-on-slang/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="what-does-it-mean">&amp;ldquo;What does it mean?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Personally, I have an innate cautiousness about using words that I don&amp;rsquo;t have a good idea what they mean. I&amp;rsquo;ve also always been one to be curious about the meanings behind words.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One word in particular I&amp;rsquo;ve always wondered about is &amp;ldquo;sucks,&amp;rdquo; specifically when used in the phrase, &amp;ldquo;that sucks.&amp;rdquo; I&amp;rsquo;ve never understood what it actually meant when people would say, &amp;ldquo;That sucks.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yes, I had my guesses, but otherwise just a suspicion that it was slang and probably wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be appropriate in some settings. So, I just never used it myself.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Whenever I heard it, I made a mental note to look it up, but I hadn&amp;rsquo;t actually remembered to do so until recently.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="looking-it-up">Looking it up&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>According to the &lt;a href="https://usdictionary.com/idioms/that-sucks/">US Dictionary&lt;/a>:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The phrase &amp;ldquo;that sucks&amp;rdquo; has its roots in American English slang from the 20th century. It&amp;rsquo;s an offshoot of older slang where &amp;ldquo;suck&amp;rdquo; was used as a term of derision or insult. Later on, it evolved into a more general expression of dissatisfaction or empathy for an unfortunate situation.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Some dictionaries say it&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em>&amp;ldquo;rude slang,&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em> while others (like this one) take a slightly different stance. Indeed, it&amp;rsquo;s at least &lt;em>derived&lt;/em> from a slang term.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It appears that there&amp;rsquo;s not a clear consensus on whether or not the phrase is considered rude, but it&amp;rsquo;s definitely not considered appropriate in professional or non-casual settings.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Based on the origin, the phrase does seem more rude and insulting than empathetic.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="a-broader-question">A broader question&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>After looking into that, I had a broader question.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Would it be correct to put slang into the same category as swearing and profanity?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To answer that, I first needed to understand what slang is.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With some research, I found that because slang varies from culture to culture and changes from generation to generation, it can be hard to pin down &lt;em>exactly&lt;/em> how to define it. Some people generally define slang as &lt;em>any&lt;/em> informal speech, while others have a tighter definition (sounds familiar, right?).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The American Heritage® Dictionary of the English Language, 5th Edition, defines slang as:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;em>noun&lt;/em> A kind of language occurring chiefly in casual and playful speech, made up typically of coinages and figures of speech that are deliberately used in place of standard terms for added raciness, humor, irreverence, or other effect.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h3 id="slang-as-euphemisms-for-cursing">Slang as euphemisms for cursing&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Most believers (if they knew) would probably agree that if the slang term is simply an euphemism for cursing or using our Heavenly Father&amp;rsquo;s name in an inappropriate way, then it would be wrong to use it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>An euphemism is using a word that doesn&amp;rsquo;t sound as bad as the original word, but the meaning is the same. I won&amp;rsquo;t give examples here, but suffice to say that there is no real difference between using a curse word and an euphemism for it since the intent is basically the same.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Keeping that in mind, what about other slang?&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="other-slang">Other slang&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s wise to think about our wording because our words are important. &lt;em>&amp;ldquo;Death and life are in the power of the tongue. (Proverbs 18:21a)&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Do we build people up and tear people down through the words we use?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Biblical standard is that we let no corrupt word proceed out of our mouth, &lt;em>&amp;ldquo;but what is good for necessary edification, that it may impart grace to the hearers.&amp;rdquo; (Ephesians 4:29)&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In essence, we should say what is going to build someone up and show love to them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The answer to my question largly depends on the definition you use to define &amp;ldquo;slang,&amp;rdquo; as well as what you consider &amp;ldquo;edifying&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m not sure whether slang (that is not a euphemism for cursing) can 100% be put into the same category as swearing and profanity.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, personally, I think it becomes a little clearer if we consider that the purpose for &lt;em>any&lt;/em> speech should be edification.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If the goal of our speech is edification, then any type of speech that isn&amp;rsquo;t edifying probably isn&amp;rsquo;t something appropriate for a believer to include in their speech. I&amp;rsquo;m not convinced that the above definition of slang indicates that it would be.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have come across various articles bringing up some good points about benefits of knowing slang. While I agree that it can be useful for culture and understanding those that do use it, that might be the extent of it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed that using slang communicates a less serious composure and one that might not always be fitting for a believer.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I think about the fact that, as believers, we are to be representatives of Yahushua, our Savior, to the world.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If we are deliberately adding &lt;em>&amp;ldquo;racy, irreverent, or rude&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em> words to our speech, are we necessarily being a good witness?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Looking Ahead</title><link>https://noahrahm.com/posts/looking-ahead/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://noahrahm.com/posts/looking-ahead/</guid><description>&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Two-hundred and fifty&amp;rdquo;, I replied.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>He paused and nodded, giving me the opportunity to comment further.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I told him a brand new recliner of the same type costs upwards of $800, but I couldn&amp;rsquo;t imagine how someone could pay that much for a recliner. I thought, &amp;ldquo;800 dollars seems like a lot of money to pay for a single piece of furniture.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>He replied with a neat perspective I had evidently forgotten the moment before.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>He explained how, when you think about it, if the recliner lasts you 10 years and you use it even 1 hour a day and it makes your life better then in reality you are only paying cents per day for the recliner. And even if you didn&amp;rsquo;t use it that much, it provided comfortable seating that contributed to your happiness and, in many cases, your health.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>He was right. It&amp;rsquo;s all a matter of &lt;em>perspective&lt;/em> to see the &lt;em>value&lt;/em> of investing in the long term rather than just thinking about the upfront cost.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>According to &lt;a href="https://cozyseating.com/how-long-should-recliner-last/">this site&lt;/a>, a recliner should last 7-15 years.
Taking the average of that, which is 11 years, and saying that someone uses the recliner just twice everyday (a pretty a modest estimate for most people) I thought I would do the math:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre tabindex="0">&lt;code>365 days x 11 years x 2 uses per day = 8,030 uses
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;pre tabindex="0">&lt;code>$800.00/8,030 = $0.09962...
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;p>So, if the recliner originally cost $800.00 and it was used &lt;em>just twice per day&lt;/em> for the estimated 11 year lifetime of the recliner, that would be &lt;strong>less than 10 cents per use&lt;/strong>. For someone that used it more or had it longer, it would be even less.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Indeed, in order to justify the upfront cost, you would need to have the long term benefits in mind -how the recliner would make your life better. If someone only looked at the here and now, 800 dollars they would have to give up in the &lt;em>short-term&lt;/em>, then they would likely miss seeing the real value of investing in it for their &lt;em>long-term&lt;/em> comfort. (I hope I&amp;rsquo;m not starting to sound like a recliner advertisement&amp;hellip;)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>His point stuck with me for the rest of the day. It really reminded me of this life and our walk to Yahweh, our Heavenly Father, looking ahead into eternity.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yes, we endure trials and persecution for His name&amp;rsquo;s sake. Yes, we give up our flesh, deny ourselves, and take up our &lt;a href="https://biblehub.com/greek/4716.htm">stauros&lt;/a> daily to follow Yahushua. However, when you look at this life as the passing vapor it is and into eternity, then you see that the passing afflictions, trials and things we give up now now are nothing in comparison to what awaits us in eternity. Nothing is worth holding on to in this world.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>2 Cor. 4:16-18&lt;/strong> Therefore we do not lose heart. Even though our outward man is perishing, yet the inward man is being renewed day by day. For our &lt;strong>light affliction, which is but for a moment, is working for us a far more exceeding and eternal weight of glory&lt;/strong>, while we do not look at the things which are seen, but at the things which are not seen. &lt;strong>For the things which are seen are temporary, but the things which are not seen are eternal&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s all about &lt;em>perspective&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The earthly, here and now isn&amp;rsquo;t so valuable when compared to the spiritual, heavenly things of Yahweh. As the hymn says, &lt;em>&amp;ldquo;and the things of earth grow strangely dim, in the light of His glory and grace&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Too often we focus on what&amp;rsquo;s going on in our lives or look at the world and question whether it is worth it. However, if we cannot find joy and strength in our present circumstances, then we can look to our bright future, just as our Savior Yahushua did in His moments of agony and anguish.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Matt. 26:39&lt;/strong> He went a little farther and fell on His face, and prayed, saying, &amp;ldquo;O My Father, if it is possible, let this cup pass from Me; nevertheless, &lt;strong>not as I will, but as You will.&lt;/strong>&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Probably some of the most heart-stirring words ever. He gave up His will in surrender to the Father.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Hebrews 12:2&lt;/strong> Looking unto Yahushua, the author and finisher of our faith, &lt;strong>who for the joy that was set before Him endured the &lt;a href="https://biblehub.com/greek/4716.htm">stauros&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>, despising the shame, and has sat down at the right hand of the throne of Yahweh.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>We should remember that if all Yahweh did was deliver us from our sins then we ought to be more than thankful. But He also gave us His great and precious promises, including eternal life through His Son Yahushua.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>2 Peter 1:2-3&lt;/strong> Grace and peace be multiplied to you in the knowledge of Yahweh and of Yahushua our Master, as His divine power has given to us all things that pertain to life and godliness, through the knowledge of Him who called us by glory and virtue, by &lt;strong>which have been given to us exceedingly great and precious promises&lt;/strong>, that through these you may be partakers of the divine nature, having escaped the corruption that is in the world through lust.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>1 John 3:1-3&lt;/strong> &lt;strong>Behold what manner of love the Father has bestowed on us, that we should be called children of Yahweh!&lt;/strong> Therefore the world does not know us, because it did not know Him. Beloved, now we are children of Yahweh; and it has not yet been revealed what we shall be, but we know that when He is revealed, &lt;strong>we shall be like Him, for we shall see Him as He is&lt;/strong>. And everyone who has this hope in Him purifies himself, just as He is pure.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>When we realize that we deserve condemnation and death but He gives us life instead, we see how amazing His love, grace, and mercy is.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>1 John 4:19&lt;/strong> We love Him because &lt;strong>He first loved us.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Romans 5:6-11&lt;/strong> For when we were still without strength, in due time Messiah died for the unrighteous. For scarcely for a righteous man will one die; yet perhaps for a good man someone would even dare to die. But &lt;strong>Yahweh demonstrates His own love toward us, in that while we were still sinners, Messiah died for us.&lt;/strong> Much more then, having now been justified by His blood, we shall be saved from wrath through Him. For if when we were enemies we were reconciled to Yahweh through the death of His Son, much more, having been reconciled, &lt;strong>we shall be saved by His life&lt;/strong>. And not only that, but we also rejoice in Yahweh through our Master Yahushua Messiah, through whom we have now received the reconciliation.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>The sad thing is, many people do see the value in giving up $800 (or more) for a recliner&amp;rsquo;s earthly comfort, but they do not want to give up themselves and humbly walk with Yahushua for &lt;em>far, far greater eternal benefits.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>May we have the right perspective and see that serving Yahweh is not only worth whatever we give up and go through in this life, but is the only way to have true joy and peace in this life and the next.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Is It Right to Download YouTube Videos?</title><link>https://noahrahm.com/posts/is-it-right-to-download-youtube-videos/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://noahrahm.com/posts/is-it-right-to-download-youtube-videos/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="why-the-question">Why the question?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>With how popular YouTube is, chances are you either had this question cross your mind or didn&amp;rsquo;t even think about it and went to download videos using one of the free &amp;ldquo;YouTube video downloaders&amp;rdquo; available online.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My motivation behind writing this article is to provoke some thought on this topic as well as just in general about the ethics of breaking TOS (Terms of Service) agreements, software licenses, or EULAs (End User License Agreements).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Unfortunately, people feel safe doing things that so many others do. However, just because everyone else does it does not necessarily make it right.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="answering-the-question">Answering the question&lt;/h3>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Should we use &amp;ldquo;YouTube video downloaders&amp;rdquo; or other software to download YouTube videos?&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>As far as I am concerned, I believe the answer is a clear &lt;strong>no&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>1. It&amp;rsquo;s against the YouTube Terms of Service (TOS)&lt;/strong> to download content outside of the player or download links they provide (more on that later). You agreed to these terms when you created the account, so I mean, that&amp;rsquo;s basically lying if you had no intent to abide by the terms.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/t/terms#c3e2907ca8">YouTube TOS&lt;/a> states:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>You are not allowed to [&amp;hellip;] access, reproduce, download, distribute, transmit, broadcast, display, sell, license, alter, modify or otherwise use any part of the Service or any Content except: (a) as expressly authorized by the Service; or (b) with prior written permission from YouTube and, if applicable, the respective rights holders.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>2. The ads on these third-party YouTube video downloader sites are often malicious&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve watched as someone used one of these sites (against my advice), where halfway through the download, a popup appeared with a download button to download malicious software. You could easily think that the popup was the download for your video, when it wasn&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Many of the ads are just downright deceptive and immoral, which shows the sort of character the people running these sites have.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="what-is-our-standard">What is our standard?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>I used to download videos from YouTube using external software for offline viewing, before I knew that it was a violation of the YouTube TOS. However, ignorance isn&amp;rsquo;t much of an excuse and I no longer do so.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I think about how, if I am willing to break the TOS to download a video from YouTube, then what keeps me from doing anything else against the terms?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In another sense, being a software developer that creates software and website licenses and terms myself, I have to ask myself another question.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>If I am willing to disregard the terms of other websites, then how can I expect &lt;em>others&lt;/em> to abide by the terms or license I create for a website or software?&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>That would be hypocritical.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="video-copyright">Video copyright&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>There is also copyright to think about. The video creators give YouTube a license to show the content through the platform, but that does not automatically give you the right to use or watch the video outside of the platform.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As someone that posts videos on YouTube myself, I think about how I feel about people downloading my videos without my permission and against YouTube&amp;rsquo;s TOC.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>While I don&amp;rsquo;t necessarily mind, it&amp;rsquo;s still not a good feeling.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="its-not-illegal-or-is-it">It&amp;rsquo;s not &amp;ldquo;illegal&amp;rdquo;. Or is it?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Now, I&amp;rsquo;ve seen other articles and videos where people will say that downloading a video against the terms isn&amp;rsquo;t &amp;ldquo;illegal&amp;rdquo; in some cases, so it&amp;rsquo;s fine. However, YouTube could suspend your account and sue you for breaching their TOS.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>YouTube has tried to take down these external download sites, but it seems they don&amp;rsquo;t because its too much hassle. Too many people download videos using these external sites, and YouTube has never actually sued anyone for downloading content.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That said, this article is not about what is legal or illegal in the sense of what you can get away with. This is about whether it&amp;rsquo;s really right to download videos from YouTube using these external sites.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="so-is-it-right">So, is it right?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>I think sometimes we get lazy and careless, especially if we don&amp;rsquo;t think something will be enforced. However, what&amp;rsquo;s wrong is still wrong, even if you don&amp;rsquo;t see the consequences right away or at all.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ultimately, if you&amp;rsquo;re a believer, what others do is of no consequence. Just because so many people do it and get away with it doesn&amp;rsquo;t make it okay. Is it right according to Scripture? That is the question.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>From what I can see, just the fact that you have to break your word to disregard the YouTube terms of service in order to download videos from YouTube using external sites gives a really clear clue.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;You shall not follow a crowd to do evil.&amp;rdquo; -Exodus 23:2a&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Lying lips are an abomination to Yahweh, But those who deal truthfully are His delight.&amp;rdquo;&amp;quot; -Proverbs 12:22&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Do not lie to one another, since you have put off the old man with his deeds.&amp;rdquo; -Colossians 3:9&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h4 id="an-example-to-illustrate">An example to illustrate&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Imagine you have a rental room at your house.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now, you set certain rules that they must abide by during their stay, one of which is that anything in the room (towels, the mirror, the lamp, etc.) must stay in the room. Imagine them, right after agreeing to the rules, taking your stuff outside for one reason or another and saying, &amp;ldquo;Well, everyone else does it&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I think we would all feel disrespected by the guest.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, if you download videos from YouTube using these external sites, &lt;em>especially&lt;/em> if you don&amp;rsquo;t have permission from the creator, then you are not just disrespecting the platform but the creator too.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="is-it-ever-right-then">Is it ever right, then?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>So, is there ever a time when it would be okay to download a video from YouTube using external sites?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Some people will point to CC (Creative Commons) licensed content or content where the creator says that users are free to download the video if they want.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The problem is that it &lt;em>could&lt;/em> still be a violation of the YouTube TOS. (I don&amp;rsquo;t have full clarity for CC licensed content).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I once had a client that had two YouTube channels and wanted to combine them into one. One of the channels only had one video. However, they had forgotten their login information for the account. So they couldn&amp;rsquo;t just download the video through YouTube Studio and reupload it to the other channel.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There was the temptation to just use an external YouTube downloader to retrieve the video. After all, it was &lt;em>his video&lt;/em>, right? It even had his name in the video title.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, we both agreed that it wasn&amp;rsquo;t even an option to violate the TOS by doing so. Instead, I linked to the single video, and that worked just fine.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="ethical-legal-alternatives">Ethical, Legal Alternatives&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Now, you&amp;rsquo;re probably wondering, &amp;ldquo;So what should I do if I&amp;rsquo;m on a limited data plan or want to watch videos offline for another reason?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I see two ways someone could legally and ethically download a YouTube video:&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="youtube-premium">YouTube Premium&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>It appears YouTube allows downloading videos for offline viewing with YouTube Premium. This is what the &amp;ldquo;links that they provide&amp;rdquo; exception in the TOS refers to. Now, I&amp;rsquo;ve never had Premium myself but it is an option to consider if you are wanting offline videos.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="ask-the-creator-directly">Ask the creator directly&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Yes, it&amp;rsquo;s a hassle, but just ask the creator to give you a link to the video on Google Drive, Dropbox, or another file sharing service.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This may actually be an even better option than YouTube Premium since you totally bypass any involvement of YouTube, acknowledge the creator, and get their direct permission to download their content. Now, obviously, the creator is not always going to accept your request. They may say &amp;ldquo;no&amp;rdquo; for one reason or another, and that is understandable.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Other creators may already have a way for you to download their videos offline, though sometimes it is only via a paywall.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="conclusion">Conclusion&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>I think it is pretty clear that we should not be downloading videos from YouTube in ways that violate the YouTube TOS. Instead, we should be respectful of the platform and the creators and either subscribe to YouTube Premium or ask the creator for their video directly.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In a broader sense, I believe we should be careful to abide by whatever agreements we make, whether it&amp;rsquo;s with the software on your PC, a streaming platform like YouTube, or your next-door neighbor.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Life Lessons from 2022</title><link>https://noahrahm.com/posts/life-lessons-2022/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://noahrahm.com/posts/life-lessons-2022/</guid><description>&lt;p>In the past year I&amp;rsquo;ve made a greater effort to look for what Yahweh, our Heavenly Father, is try to show me in every situation. There is always something to learn, even in the darkest of situations. :)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Life is a journey. A believer&amp;rsquo;s life is continuing to grow in Yahushua (commonly called &amp;ldquo;Jesus&amp;rdquo;). It is following the footsteps of the Savior. Learning little, by little.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ll say that it is much easier to learn the lessons He is trying to teach you the first time. Though, if you don&amp;rsquo;t stop to think about what He is showing you, then you probably won&amp;rsquo;t learn it.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="lessons">Lessons&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>So, here is my reflection of life lessons that stand out the most from what I&amp;rsquo;ve learned this past year. I&amp;rsquo;ve intentionally left these rather general so that you can see how these can apply in difference circumstances.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="precedence">Precedence&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Things need to be Yahweh&amp;rsquo;s way from the very start, to begin with. The first meeting of something is probably how the rest will be. First impression &lt;em>is&lt;/em> important. Subsequent meetings will probably follow the same pattern and it is hard to steer it right again.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="confrontation">Confrontation&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>As hard as it is, if you can&amp;rsquo;t overlook something in another believer, you must confront the person and make it right. Follow Matthew 18.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>15&lt;/strong> &amp;ldquo;Moreover if your brother sins against you, go and tell him his fault between you and him alone. If he hears you, you have gained your brother. &lt;strong>16&lt;/strong> But if he will not hear, take with you one or two more, that &amp;lsquo;by the mouth of two or three witnesses every word may be established.&amp;rsquo; &lt;strong>17&lt;/strong> And if he refuses to hear them, tell it to the church. But if he refuses even to hear the church, let him be to you like a heathen and a tax collector.&amp;rdquo; -Matt. 18:15-17&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Don&amp;rsquo;t wait to resolve an issue with someone if it cannot be forgotten. The longer it goes on, the harder it will be to resolve. Glossing over problems and avoiding talking about them &lt;strong>doesn&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/strong> solve the problem.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="expectations">Expectations&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Misunderstandings and conflicts can happen when both parties are not clear on their expectations. Be clear what you expect from others and clarify their expectations of you.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="loyalty">Loyalty&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Remember who you are working for and who your loyalty belongs to. People &lt;strong>will&lt;/strong> fail. People &lt;strong>will&lt;/strong> have conflicts.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Remember that you are not working for men but for Yahweh. Don&amp;rsquo;t be discouraged. Be loyal to Yahweh and the calling &lt;strong>He&lt;/strong> has called you to.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Whatever you do, do your work heartily, as for Yahweh rather than for men&amp;rdquo; -Colossians 3:23&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h4 id="communication">Communication&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Remember that life is about relationships and without communication, there is no relationship.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Never be too busy to listen to others or talk to them, especially if you have a conflict. Remember that it is a two-way street. Both parties need to talk &lt;strong>and&lt;/strong> listen to the other.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Remember that the most important communication is with Yahweh through prayer.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="patience">Patience&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Wait&lt;/strong> for Yahweh&amp;rsquo;s timing and plan. Don&amp;rsquo;t rush ahead without His leading.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Trust in Yahweh with all your heart, And lean not on your own understanding; In all your ways acknowledge Him, And He shall direct your paths.&amp;rdquo; -Proverbs 3:5-6&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>However, don&amp;rsquo;t confuse patience with procrastination(!) or lack of faith.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="judgement">Judgement&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Make sure you hear both sides and have the facts before you judge a matter. Don&amp;rsquo;t be too quick to blame or release from blame.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As hard as it is, wait until you have &lt;strong>all&lt;/strong> of the information about the situation before making a judgement. Don&amp;rsquo;t feel pressured to make a judgement hastily.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="facts">Facts&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Don&amp;rsquo;t assume you have all the facts or think you know something about someone or something. It is easy to be &amp;ldquo;in the moment&amp;rdquo; and end up making up things, assuming things that aren&amp;rsquo;t true.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="self-imposed-rules">Self-Imposed Rules&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Don&amp;rsquo;t seek to establish your &lt;strong>own&lt;/strong> form of righteousness. Study the Scriptures and walk out Yahweh&amp;rsquo;s righteousness. Don&amp;rsquo;t look down on those that do not follow your self-imposed rules, even if they are good, but not necessarily from Scripture.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="appearance">Appearance&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Remember that sometimes people will assume things about you based on &lt;strong>appearance&lt;/strong> or by what you &lt;strong>don&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/strong> say as much as what you do say. Don&amp;rsquo;t take it personally if someone thinks bad of you because of it. Yahweh justifies.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="compromise">Compromise&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Compromising on what Scripture says, even a little bit, opens the door to a continuous erosion of it from your life. Once the door is open, it is hard to close. Be sure that any compromise you make &lt;strong>does not compromise your belief in Yahweh&amp;rsquo;s Word.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="jealousy">Jealousy&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Don&amp;rsquo;t get jealous of other people&amp;rsquo;s situations, etc. Jealousy stems from discontentment. The grass &lt;strong>isn&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/strong> greener on the other side of the fence. &lt;strong>Everyone&lt;/strong> has their own set of problems and they may be worse than yours. Be content where Yahweh has placed you in life.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="be-humble-be-real">Be Humble; Be Real&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Be humble, knowing that you deserve death, but Yahweh showed you mercy and grace. Show the same mercy and grace that He shows to &lt;strong>You&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Do not look down on others for what you &lt;strong>think&lt;/strong> they do not know or practice. You also have things that Yahweh is trying to get your attention about and you must be humble to even see what He is trying to teach you.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Everyone&lt;/strong> has problems and struggles they deal with. Don&amp;rsquo;t act like you have everything together when it is not the case. Even people, in general, will appreciate your honesty in admitting that you have struggles over acting like you have it all together.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="conclusion">Conclusion&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>I hope this post has blessed and encouraged you. If you would like to share life lessons &lt;strong>you&lt;/strong> have learned this past year, I would love to hear what they are in the comments below.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>